Mom!
Moon Se Guk lied,
but as for me,
I can cure Min Seo's illness.
Every single one of them...
was treated by me.
You must be hungry.
Come on, let's go inside.
Mom, can we make a quick stop
at the convenience store first?
There's something I'm really craving.
Gosh. Fine. Let's go.
Excuse me?
Are you Kang Sang Woo?
Yes, that's me.
You are?
Who are you?
It's just that...
(The Savior’s Quagmire)
(Case: Serial murders,
Guam City serial murder and desecration)
(Prosecution)
This is Cha Yi Yeon
from Violent Crimes Unit One.
I'll cut to the chase.
We've found all the victims' bodies.
But to be blunt, we didn't find them.
Lee Woo Gyeom confessed.
Where did you dump the remaining victims?
On the mid-slope of Mount Cheonggye,
facing the river,
at the 100-meter mark.
Is he trying to get a reduced sentence?
Yes. He asked me about a plea bargain.
I don't want a lighter sentence.
I want to make a different kind of deal.
To this day, the number of victims,
their identities, the body locations...
He's never given a straight answer
about any of it.
He's toying with us even as we speak.
He has no regard for human life,
He's deceiving the entire nation watching,
all while looking down on us from above.
So what's your point?
Now it's your turn to cross the line,
Prosecutor Cha.
Come over to my side.
I will personally show you in court.
How I can save a life
without so much as a scalpel.
You crazy punk...
We will be seeking the death penalty.
(The Establishment of Law and Order)
You seem more at ease today.
I just came from seeing Sang Woo.
That's just like you, Attorney Park.
What do you mean? "Just like me?"
You think you know me?
That you're a good father
who loves Min Seo more than anything...
Don't talk so casually about my daughter.
Gosh, it was a compliment.
That's a little harsh.
Did you really cure Sang Woo?
Didn't you see him walking?
That Sang Woo was cured because of you.
That's something I...
How am I supposed to believe that?
Good.
You should keep doubting me.
That's the only way
you'll want to see the real thing.
Attorney Park,
when people come back from the dead,
they come to realize
more than what meets the eye.
I was in a coma for three years
after a car accident.
I had no idea how I woke up,
much less why.
My doctor said I had a new blood mutation,
but I couldn't just take his word for it.
I was just an ordinary med student
back then.
But there was another problem.
As an aftereffect of the accident,
waves of pain would hit me out of nowhere.
The exact same pain
I felt during the car crash.
I couldn't find the cause.
So, since I was living
on borrowed time anyway,
I started experimenting on my own body.
I did all sorts of crazy things,
not caring if I died.
I injected myself with anything
that could possibly be a cure.
But then one day,
the pain was gone.
I had created a cure
for an incurable disease.
For the very disease that
they said was untreatable.
The pain, the aftereffects of the coma...
They were all gone.
You're saying you found a cure?
Yes. And I realized that method
could be used to cure other diseases too.
You can really...
You can cure the Batten disease,
can't you?
No one believed me at first.
But they all survived,
and every single person who woke up
was grateful to me.
Life and death...
It's nothing to me.
(Court)
- Bring back the death penalty!
- Bring it back!
- Harsh punishment for violent criminals!
- Punish them!
- That's Lee Woo Gyeom!
- Murderer! Killer!
- Killer!
- Murderer!
- Lee Woo Gyeom, you murderer!
- Hey, killer!
- Bring back the death penalty!
- Bring it back!
Following the arrest of
serial killer Lee Woo Gyeom,
public support for resuming executions
has been rising dramatically.
According to a recent poll,
a staggering 74.3 percent
of respondents said...
they were in favor of resuming executions.
Meanwhile, the attorney
handling Lee Woo Gyeom's trial,
Park Han Jun,
is also facing continued controversy.
Attorney Park was
formerly a prosecutor for...
the Central Investigation Department...
before becoming a civil rights attorney.
However, in recent years...
The defendant killed 17 people.
Is that correct?
Yes.
And you claim you killed them
while experimenting to create a cure?
- Yes, that's correct.
- Assuming your claim is true,
the process
in which 17 people were killed.
- Where are the records of that research?
- Your Honor.
The records in Exhibit 23 contain
the research on the 17 victims.
Your Honor.
However, the victims' bodies
are so severely mutilated...
that the National Forensic Service reports
they can't confirm their identities.
(Prosecution)
Defendant!
If your goal was research,
why dismember the victims so brutally?
If your goal was truly research, then why!
Why did Hong Jae Gwang have to be murdered
and left in such a wretched state?
(Defendant)
Your Honor.
If the defendant's true intention
was research,
would he have needed to desecrate
the victims' bodies to such an extent?
How interesting.
Therefore, we contend that this case...
is just a series of thrill kills
by a psychopathic murderer.
Your Honor.
The prosecution's assertion
of "thrill kills" is...
merely an emotional argument
with no evidence whatsoever.
Sustained.
Prosecutor, do you have any grounds?
Yes. I'll present them now.
Defendant.
You're familiar with
Jo Gyeong Chan, correct?
Yes.
Five years ago, you were hit by a car
driven by Jo Gyeong Chan,
which left you in a coma for three years.
How did you feel about that?
You must have been angry, right?
Resentful that this happened to you.
And over time,
towards the person responsible
for the accident,
you must have felt anger
and a desire for revenge.
- That's not true.
- It's not?
No, it is not.
Then why did you seek out
and murder Jo Gyeong Chan?
Jo Gyeong Chan?
Your Honor. The defendant's crimes...
were premeditated murders born
from anger and a desire for revenge.
He targeted adults whose disappearances
were unlikely to be investigated,
making this a clear case
of calculated serial murder.
I submit their traffic accident record
as evidence.
The accident between the defendant
and the victim, Jo Gyeong Chan,
- Look at him.
- Darn... He's a monster.
Stop provoking them.
I'm not provoking them. It's just absurd.
- Look at him. My goodness.
- Order!
I will have you removed
from the courtroom if not.
(Defendant)
Counsel for the defense, your rebuttal.
(Defense Counsel)
Your Honor.
The prosecution's argument...
does have some merit.
And that's because you have yet to hear
the details of how my client...
performed his treatments.
Are you saying you can explain
the treatment process?
I won't just explain it.
I'll show you firsthand.
I would like to call as witnesses
the six terminally ill patients...
whom the defendant claims to have cured.
So who are the witnesses?
I still have to find them.
What?
So you were just bluffing?
I had to shift the momentum of the trial.
It was leaning in Prosecutor Cha's favor
from the start.
You make it sound like it's my fault.
That's because it is.
Why did you have to mutilate
the bodies like that?
You only call it "mutilation"
because you see it as murder.
"Why are you dissecting a frog
so cruelly?"
That's the exact same question.
But Hong Jae Gwang was different.
Because the experiment with him
was a success.
So you drained all of his blood?
Yes, that's when I figured out
how to create the cure.
To you, when it comes to your experiments,
murder is just part of the process.
If Hong Jae Gwang's experiment failed,
you wouldn't have stopped at 17, right?
Just be honest with me.
Stop lying.
- Lie about what?
- Because you wanted to kill him.
That's why you killed him.
That's why you killed
Jo Gyeong Chan first, isn't it?
Be honest with me about your motive,
and let's focus on proving your ability.
If you're caught lying in court,
you won't escape the death penalty.
I don't care.
They won't execute me anyway.
Besides, would they really execute someone
who can cure the terminally ill?
That's only...
if your treatment is recognized.
Only if it's recognized.
That's why...
I need you to get my ability recognized
through this trial.
Get those witnesses to testify too.
That's the only way to treat Min Seo,
right?
(Hae Gang Law Firm)
(Attorney Park Han Jun)
Park Han Jun.
Do you really have to
take the Lee Woo Gyeom case?
It's not too late. Please, just drop it.
I'll try to persuade the director again.
It's fine.
How is this fine?
You're not thinking straight.
Why on earth would you agree
to defend a serial killer?
If you become the public's punching bag,
- what kind of client would hire you?
- I have to do this.
But why?
Why does it have to be you?
It's a case I have to take.
For Lee Woo Gyeom... And...
for me.
You are off the route.
Reporter Jo, it's me.
My GPS can't seem to find the place.
The roads around here are a real maze,
so it's hard to find.
What do you see around you?
Not much besides the sky,
And a long flight of stairs to my right.
- See the sky? Then you're almost here.
- Really?
I see your car.
- I see you.
- Yes. Just keep coming straight up.
Right here.
All right, you're parked, right?
You're here, Attorney Park.
Man, you must've had a hard time
getting here.
Ta-da! Cozy, right?
Goodness.
Gosh.
It feels lived in.
Here, let me take that.
This is your spot right here.
You must be thirsty.
Instant coffee or cold water?
No, I'm good.
Come on, at least let me...
Here, have a nice, cold glass.
Don't worry, the water's clean.
If six witnesses claim Lee Woo Gyeom
cured their incurable diseases,
do you think the court will see
the case a little differently?
They'd have to.
It would completely change
the motive for the murders.
Yes.
Right.
About Lee Woo Gyeom,
I heard they're moving him
to solitary confinement.
It's just a psychological tactic
to corner him.
This puts us at a disadvantage
in so many ways.
Reporter Jo.
Yes?
How about you write an article for me?
(Why Prosecution Ignores the Truth?)
It's a reporter named Jo Woo Cheol.
He's the one who's clashed with
the financial crimes unit before.
Can't you shut him up?
We don't need to respond
to this kind of tabloid trash.
I'm telling you.
He's working with Attorney Park.
With Attorney Park Han Jun?
This is exactly why I can't relax.
I told you to pay attention
to every little detail.
If we make one wrong move...
See? It just becomes a huge pain,
understand?
Yes, hello?
This is Cha Yi Yeon speaking.
Director Oh is unavailable at the moment,
so I'm taking his calls.
Yes, he's doing well,
thank you for asking.
By any chance,
are you calling about that strange article
that was published today?
Please don't worry, Chief Prosecutor.
I will take care of this precisely,
and I'll handle it with no loose ends.
Yes, of course. The director is back.
One moment, please.
Here you go.
"Precisely?"
Don't worry.
Hello, Chief Prosecutor?
This is Director Oh.
Yes.
Number 5896, in your cell.
That's him, right? The serial killer.
Look at that pretty face.
- He's got killer looks.
- Hey, new guy. Don't stare like that.
Lose the death stare.
Hey, what are you lookin' at?
Hey, look at this bastard's face.
You killed 17 people, huh?
You disrespectful punk.
Get over here.
I want a good look at your face.
Hey. Hey!
(Jaeil Hospital)
(Pediatric Ward Nurses' Station)
Min Seo.
Doctor, her breathing is unstable.
Her BP and pulse keep dropping too.
Min Seo, look at Mommy. Min Seo!
Hey. What's wrong with Min Seo?
It must have been the increased dosage.
She's stable for now,
but I'll run some more detailed tests.
Jae Hee.
Let's...
Let's try to get that new drug again.
That drug was only tested on adults.
It could be dangerous
for children like Min Seo.
But still,
we can't just go through
the same thing day after day.
Doing the same thing over and over
is what's keeping our Min Seo alive.
Listen to me.
I think about our Min Seo all the time.
They said no other patient has held on
as long as our Min Seo has.
We've done so well up to now,
so our Min Seo will be fine.
You're right.
Our Min Seo...
will get healthy again.
And I will make sure she does.
I'm sorry.
Appearing in court...
It's too much for me.
Ma'am,
we just need you to testify...
that Sang Woo was treated...
by Lee Woo Gyeom. That's all.
My Sang Woo...
Even though he's recovered,
it's still not easy for him
to face the world.
I don't want the whole world to know...
the fact that my son was sick.
If people find out he was treated
by a murderer, what will they think?
I'm sorry.
Wait... Ma'am!
What about the patient, Oh Min Gyu?
Have you reached him?
His testimony is on record,
but we haven't confirmed his identity yet.
Also, all six patients treated
by Lee Woo Gyeom are refusing to testify.
If we want to bring them in,
we might have to subpoena them.
No, absolutely not. If we do that,
we might not get the testimony we need.
- So, what do we do?
- We just have to keep...
trying to persuade them.
(Oh Min Gyu, 25 years old,
Recovered Batten disease)
(True Rehabilitation)
(Strive to Live Righteously)
Something about that punk
just rubs me the wrong way.
I heard that he killed
17 people all by himself.
Seventeen people?
- What crew is he with?
- He's not with any crew.
They say he came up as a lone wolf.
A lone wolf.
Go on.
Stare all you want.
Once we're in the same cell,
I'll beat you senseless.
- Damn it.
- You fool!
(Please be quiet.)
Changing the witnesses' minds...
is going to take some time.
How cheap.
And to think they were begging me
to save them.
Of all the patients you treated,
by any chance,
do you remember a patient
named Oh Min Gyu?
Yes. The one with Batten disease.
Can you get in touch with him?
No.
Once their treatment is over, that's it.
I see.
But it must be nice to be Min Seo.
Having a father who only cares about her.
Focus on your case.
Alright, then.
Don't you have some kind of record
of how you treated them?
- Of course I do.
- You do?
But the witnesses have to testify
for the court to admit them as evidence.
Since the witnesses can't testify now,
just submitting those records...
is our best shot.
If you go to my study,
there should be a red notebook.
That's my research log.
But I'm pretty sure
the police have already taken it.
They did?
"Human Clinical Trial Results."
(Oh Min Gyu, Male, Batten Disease)
Batten Disease.
(Oh Min Gyu, 25 years old,
Recovered Batten disease)
Hey!
Stop right there.
I said stop!
I'm sorry. I won't do it again.
Please, just let me go.
Hey everyone, this is legit the place
where Lee Woo Gyeom...
dismembered his victim. Check this out.
- Hey.
- The vibe in here is insane, right?
Is this that "dare challenge"
that's going around?
Yes. If this video blows up,
I can get ad revenue.
- And the top guys make over a grand.
- Okay, I get it. Hey, Attorney Park.
As you know,
we can't guard the scene 24 hours a day.
And besides,
this is on the kid who crossed the tape,
right?
Yes, I'm sorry.
You.
Listen to me carefully.
If you lie, you could be charged
with trespassing and obstructing justice,
which means up to three years in prison...
and a fine of up to five grand.
Understand?
Tell me the truth.
Did you go inside...
or not?
I swear I only filmed nearby.
Besides, the doors were all locked.
So you tried the doors, didn't you?
You can't lie about this.
If you lie, you'll be in huge trouble.
- You hear me?
- I'm sorry.
I'm really sorry.
I'll delete everything, I swear.
- I'm really...
- Tell me the truth!
Yes... I opened it.
(Court)
You're here early.
We keep running into each other.
I thought we were on opposite sides.
How's Chief Oh doing?
You mean Chief Oh?
Back when I was on the bench,
everyone was in an uproar
about some hothead who had just joined,
and he told me he was the one
who took you under his wing.
You mean the troublemaker,
the top student at the Training Institute?
You should worry less
about other people...
and more about the murderer
you're defending.
Hello.
I know you're all very busy,
so I appreciate your cooperation.
The defense witness will be present,
- correct?
- Yes.
That is correct.
At the next hearing,
based on the witnesses' testimonies,
we'll determine if the crime's motive
was truly to heal people or not.
We will examine that closely.
A change in motive...
- won't change the outcome of this case.
- But the sentencing guidelines...
could change, though.
Look,
he killed 17 people.
Let's not do this here.
Save it for the courtroom.
You saw Reporter Jo's article, didn't you?
Seemed pretty accurate to me.
And what part of it is supposedly factual?
Why?
If it's not true, then prove it.
Stop whining about it like a child.
A child?
You were my student once.
So you still seem like one to me.
(Reporter Jo Woo Cheol, Daehan Daily)
Give my regards to Reporter Jo.
I'll be on my way.
(Criminal Court, Civil Petitions Office)
Hey, Reporter Jo, it's me.
- Attorney Park, we have a huge problem.
- What?
They're raiding the office right now!
It's total chaos!
I'm almost there. I can see the office.
Hang on.
No, they say my article is defamation,
violates the Comms Network Act,
and is an obstruction of justice.
Can they really raid an office for this?
We know you're in there!
Open up before we break the door down!
They're breaking the door. They broke it!
They're in!
Please hurry... Hey, wait a minute!
Hold on!
Hey, what do you think you're doing?
You don't even have a warrant!
Please cooperate.
Let's just get this over with
quickly and painlessly.
Look who it is.
You should've just opened the door.
- I was on the phone.
- Hey! Hold on a minute!
Hold on, everyone.
Let me see the search warrant.
This is all by the book.
If we go back to Prosecutor Cha
empty-handed...
So just step aside, please.
Go ahead.
What are you doing here anyway?
But hold on a second!
Everyone, just stop for a second.
I...
happen to share this office space.
So anything that belongs to me...
is absolutely off-limits. Understood?
Sir, isn't this your desk?
Your business cards are right here.
About that...
I put them in the wrong spot.
This is my desk right here.
Yes. That's right.
That's actually my desk.
Yes, go ahead and take it.
Sir, you're making this difficult.
This is clear obstruction of justice.
Fine, then. Take whatever you want.
But just know I'll be suing you
for larceny...
for illegally taking my property.
We'll see who has the bigger headache.
Just you wait.
Man, what a chaotic day.
I thought I was going to lose my mind.
That was Prosecutor Cha's doing, right?
I heard she comes from
a pretty powerful family.
She's the youngest daughter
of Sejin Group, right?
That's right.
So what's the bad blood between you two?
She was my student back when
I taught at the Training Institute.
But regardless of her family,
she was the sharpest student
I ever taught...
and the biggest pain in my neck.
Gosh. For a student to be that rude
to her teacher...
Man, today's been a mess.
When I'm stressed, I like to eat.
Let's get a drink.
Hey, Min Gyeong! Over here!
Attorney Park.
- What's this?
- I invited her.
Have you been well?
Yes, I've been fine.
- It's been a while.
- Yes.
So, are you really not going
to hire me back?
CEO Heo said Hae Gang will pay my salary,
and that it's okay for me
to come and help you.
Just stay at Hae Gang
and keep doing your job there.
Attorney Park.
After you left, I wasn't assigned
to a new supervising attorney,
so all I do every day is make copies.
This has to be better than that.
Gosh, what are you talking about?
Attorney Park.
What if we let Min Gyeong here...
try to meet with a witness?
The witnesses?
You haven't secured a witness yet?
Not yet.
Since it's a serial murder case,
most witnesses are reluctant to cooperate.
Then let me give it a try.
What?
I happen to be amazing
at getting people on board.
For example, at my college festival,
I set up all the lonely students
on group dates,
and our pop-up bar broke the all-time
school sales record. That was all me.
But...
- Recruiting a witness isn't exactly...
- You don't need a certificate for that.
I don't have a certificate,
but I do have confidence.
Maybe it's because
we're a couple of dreary faces...
that it hasn't been working out.
I know I can do a really good job.
Please?
For crying out loud.
What's gotten into you two?
All right, fine. Then...
Min Gyeong has no field experience,
so Reporter Jo, show her the ropes.
Of course. That's my specialty.
Min Gyeong, looking forward to working
with you. I'm Jo Woo Cheol.
Hey, I'm just going to speak casually.
Since you decided
to speak informally first,
I'll do the same.
- What?
- I'm just kidding, sir.
- Well, then, shall we have a drink?
- All right.
- All right, glasses up.
- Yes.
- Cheers.
- Good.
Lee Woo Gyeom will surely pay
for his crimes, right?
But if it's true that he really cured
an incurable disease...
so that he can help even more people,
we have to at least give it a shot,
don't we?
Ma'am.
For the other patients and families
who are going through the same pain,
please,
I'm begging you.
I understand.
I'll testify.
Thank you, ma'am.
There's something.
I received this.
(From Lee Woo Gyeom)
(To the sea)
What in the world is this letter?
Did Mr. Lee Woo Gyeom really write this?
If word gets out that I was sick,
it'll hurt my reputation at work.
Please don't worry.
Information about witnesses
is kept strictly confidential.
- And we'll...
- But this is going too far.
You're threatening to leak
my personal information to the press?
You can promise me that nothing
will happen to my Sang Woo, right?
Look, I'll agree to testify,
but I won't be threatened like this.
I promise I'll do whatever it takes...
to make sure you're not harmed by this.
I'm counting on you.
This is the only way
the witnesses will testify.
Nothing good will come
from provoking the witnesses.
You have to provoke them
to get a reaction.
You think all witnesses are on your side?
They could do something unpredictable.
From now on,
everything and anything
related to this trial,
you run by me first.
Got it?
Yes.
Prosecutor Cha.
Here's the defense's witness list.
Thank you.
The mother of a patient
Lee Woo Gyeom saved...
and an actual patient he treated
are being called as witnesses.
Polio.
Blood cancer.
(Kang Sang Woo, 18 years old,
Congenital incurable polio)
Kang Sang Woo.
Incurable polio.
He had never walked a single step
in his life.
Right.
Apparently, at a support group
for families with incurable diseases,
Sang Woo's mother met Lee Woo Gyeom
by Song Tae Jin's sister.
Mr. Song had terminal blood cancer,
but he's now been declared fully cured.
Of the six patients...
with incurable diseases
that Lee Woo Gyeom treated,
we've been unable to contact
the other four.
Let's focus on the confirmed witnesses,
Kang Sang Woo's mother...
and Mr. Song Tae Jin.
The court will absolutely want to know...
how Lee Woo Gyeom treated these people.
So the question is how, in what way,
we should disclose that. That's...
That's the challenge.
Attorney Park.
You're worried about that letter he sent
to the witnesses, aren't you?
Yes.
The witnesses...
I didn't want to force them to testify.
Should we file for a postponement then?
No, no.
Given how impulsive Lee Woo Gyeom is,
there's no telling what he might do next.
Let's find a better option for now.
And do our absolute best...
to be prepared.
Well then, no time like the present.
Let's get right to it, good?
Sure, sounds good.
I'd much rather pull an all-nighter
than just be on copy duty.
So, should I finally show you
what I'm made of?
- Thanks for all your hard work.
- Good job.
- Bye.
- See you later.
Today is the 4th hearing of the 1st trial
of the Lee Woo Gyeom case.
The focus of this trial
is expected to be...
on the witnesses' testimony
about the treatment.
Witness.
Is it true you entrusted the defendant,
Lee Woo Gyeom,
with treating your son, Sang Woo,
- for his polio?
- Yes.
That's correct.
Then could you please describe
what happened at that time?
He came with a bag of medical instruments.
And...
he injected what he called a "cure"
into Sang Woo's arm.
And what were Sang Woo's symptoms
after the injection?
Sang Woo seemed tired and fell asleep.
He didn't wake up until dawn.
How do you...
- remember that after all this time?
- That morning,
Sang Woo suddenly cried out and stood up.
He stood up?
So that everyone
in this court can hear you,
please say that again...
in a loud, clear voice.
Yes.
He stood up!
Could you describe that moment...
in more detail?
"Mom! Mom, look at this!"
That's what he shouted.
I was shocked and rushed to his room,
and when I got there,
he was standing on his own two feet.
That's right.
Not once in 18 years.
Sang Woo, who could never stand,
was standing there,
completely on his own,
right there in front of the witness.
Witness,
that is the truth, is it not?
Yes.
- He was standing all on his own.
- And after that,
did Sang Woo's condition get worse,
or did it not?
It did not.
It was as if Sang Woo
had been given a new life.
He told me how incredibly grateful he was
to Mr. Lee Woo Gyeom.
He asked me to be sure to tell him that.
Thank you.
I have no further questions, Your Honor.
Prosecutor.
You may begin your cross-examination.
Witness, how many hospitals gave you
the incurable polio diagnosis for him?
Around seven, I believe.
And did you tell each new hospital
of the previous diagnosis?
Yes. So they'd know
what treatments he'd already had.
Was that really the reason?
Your insurance payouts for Sang Woo
were over 80,000 dollars in total.
Isn't it true
you couldn't risk a different diagnosis?
Your Honor.
This line of questioning
is completely irrelevant...
to the efficacy of the treatment.
I am trying to establish that
if she intentionally shared the diagnosis,
even if the incurable polio
was a misdiagnosis,
the same diagnosis
would simply have been repeated.
I'll allow it. You may continue.
I'd like to call Seo Yeong Seok
from the National Forensic Service.
When a prior diagnosis is shared,
the same mistake is more likely to occur.
Can't they just ignore
the previous records?
When you see dozens of patients a day,
it's hard to question the first diagnosis.
What about in the case of Kang Sang Woo?
Since there are no recorded cases
of a full recovery from incurable polio,
- I think Sang Woo had another disease.
- Just a moment.
- So the diagnosis was a misdiagnosis?
- Yes.
The disease most often misdiagnosed
as incurable polio...
is Segawa's disease.
The two present such similar symptoms
that even doctors get confused. However,
unlike incurable polio,
Segawa's disease...
is completely curable.
In your expert opinion, what he treated
was not incurable polio, is that correct?
Yes, that is correct.
To come out now and say
Sang Woo had Segawa's disease...
You can't possibly conclude that, can you?
It's more of a stretch to believe
an incurable disease was cured.
Either way,
the defendant, Lee Yu Gyeom...
- It's a fact that he did treat him.
- Your Honor,
the defense submitted no prior evidence
regarding Segawa's disease.
Sustained.
Attorney Park. Confine your questions
to the defendant's original claim.
Nothing further.
The court will recess for 30 minutes.
And then proceed with the examination
of the second witness.
Let's go.
(Defendant)
- Attorney Park.
Did you get a hold of him?
I can't get in touch with Song Tae Jin.
Right, keep trying.
Okay.
Attorney Park,
please begin your examination
of the second witness.
Your Honor.
There's an issue with
the witness's appearance,
so I request a postponement.
Isn't witness testimony
the crux of this trial?
A postponement is unacceptable.
The witness is present in the courtroom.
Attorney Park,
what is the meaning of this?
Your Honor.
If the defense is not going to call
Mr. Song Tae Jin to the stand,
I request that the prosecution be allowed
to call him as our witness.
Your Honor, the witness
the prosecution is referring to...
has been watching
the previous witness's testimony...
and is likely feeling a great deal
of psychological distress.
So, I object to the prosecution's request
to call him to the stand.
Both of you, please be seated.
The court will confer,
and then issue a ruling.
The prosecution's request
to call the witness...
is granted.
Witness.
Is it true you also received treatment
from the defendant, Mr. Lee Yu Gyeom?
Yes, that's correct.
And were you completely cured?
No, I wasn't cured.
I'm receiving medical treatment again.
That man is not a doctor.
He's a complete con man.
He threatened to leak private information,
my medical records, and family details.
Don't be fooled by him.
Nothing further, Your Honor.
(High Court, District Court)
Excuse me, Song Tae Jin.
Wait a second.
What on earth...
- Why did you do that?
- Do what?
I'm asking why you testified
like that in court.
Because it's the truth.
I'm getting worse again.
But you clearly said...
- You were cured.
- I thought I was.
But it came back.
Don't you ever...
come near me again.
Attorney Park.
Is this really the best you can do?
How are we supposed to
win the trial like this?
You're the one who caused this mess.
You're blaming me for this?
Yes. This whole thing happened because
you threatened Song Tae Jin.
I think you're mistaken.
If I can't prove my abilities,
Min Seo will die too.
You... I told you...
not to talk so casually about my daughter.
That's my point.
Just let me prove myself already.
That's all it would take,
but you were fumbling with the witnesses,
so I had to step in.
You stepped in and ruined everything,
you son of a bitch!
(Fresh Sashimi)
Mr. Song Tae Jin.
I'm sorry for showing up unannounced.
If you don't mind,
I'd just like to ask you a few things.
They told me I was completely cured,
but since he's not a real doctor,
so I got worried and went back
to the hospital.
Sure enough, I had a relapse.
So in other words,
Lee Woo Gyeom's treatment didn't work?
That's right.
In time, Sang Woo...
will end up just like me.
But after his treatment
from Lee Woo Gyeom,
Sang Woo never received
any hospital treatments.
To be clear, you went to the hospital
after Lee Woo Gyeom's supposed cure?
Yes.
So then...
Prosecutor, you can't let the patient
get another procedure.
If it interferes with my methods,
he'll never be able to recover.
So your condition got worse
when you resumed hospital treatment.
What?
Not because of Lee Woo Gyeom.
Your records and witnesses
have been refuted,
- so how can I possibly trust you anymore?
- What I want right now...
is to prove my abilities
so I can treat people who are suffering.
My intentions are good.
Why can't you convey that properly?
Because...
that's not what you really want.
Would someone
with such good intentions...
treat the witnesses like garbage?
You, be honest with me.
Why do you really want to prove yourself?
You want me to tell you?
Are you sure you can handle it?