=The Truth=
=Episode 6=
(Bowang)
Excuse me.
Where is the table reserved by Miss Han?
Sir.
Second floor.
Thank you.
No problem.
Little Zhao.
Where should I sit?
- Next to her.
- Next to him.
I'll sit there.
Next to Little Zhao.
Off duty now, let's have a drink.
No alcohol. I might get called in.
Alright.
You guys are killjoys.
Then I'll drink by myself.
Yu.
One pot of spirit and two colas.
- Okay.
- Spirit?
You're really something.
I'll open it for you.
I'm not drinking.
I'll have water.
I'll have it.
Did you tell Little Qian
that you're pursuing me?
No.
What for?
You know I like Little Qian.
I know you like Little Qian.
But Little Qian doesn't like you.
You're single, and I'm single.
So I can pursue you.
Don't need his permission, but yours.
I haven't agreed.
I know you haven't.
That's why I'm pursuing you.
Fine.
You're paying today.
No problem.
This place isn't cheap.
Officer, can your salary cover this?
Don't worry. I've got Qian here.
She owns this place.
I opened this place for him.
Try this.
This.
This is way too much.
Not at all.
You need nutrients. Eat more.
All are your favorites.
Just this once.
Don't do this again.
Too much to finish.
You eat too.
Got it.
Next time, let's eat at my place.
Your place?
I opened a restaurant nearby.
You know the ropes.
Come try the food sometime.
Why open a restaurant suddenly?
You cops are busy,
but you still need to eat.
If you eat at my restaurant,
I won't charge you.
Actually, I wanted
you to come eat often,
then we'd see each other more.
Han Zhao, I've told you.
It won't work.
Why not?
We're both single and available.
And I've got this.
I support you
to open a restaurant.
But if you say it's for me,
I won't accept it.
Got it.
Enough talk, just eat.
Quit rambling.
Eat this. Your favorite.
You eat too.
If you say so,
I won't come again.
Well...
There are plenty of fish in the sea.
Why only love Little Qian?
You're not his type.
Do you know his type?
Of course, I do.
He likes long-haired,
gentle,
simple,
and delicate girls.
You're not that type.
You told him about Chen Yumo?
This way.
Mr. Pang, you're here.
The room your booked is upstairs.
This way.
Thank you.
Please, this way.
What would you like to eat?
Salt-baked mackerel pike.
Thank you.
Pretty woman?
Do you know her?
Colleagues.
Same department with us.
I really underestimated
you police officers.
Your spending level is quite high.
I think Ziwu
is here for another blind date.
Blind date?
That guy comes here often.
He brings a different woman each time.
I often
come to this place,
so I booked here.
The environment is nice.
Take a look at the menu.
If you don't like it here,
we can change another place.
No need.
Anything will do.
Alright.
Let's eat first.
By the way,
I booked a KTV room.
After dinner, we can go sing songs.
Mr. Pang.
I need to explain something to you.
Actually, I'm not interested
in this blind date today.
The reason I came
is that I didn't want
to embarrass Mr. Zhao.
After today's meal,
I think
we won't meet again.
So let's split
the meal cost.
It's okay.
Take a look at the menu and order food.
I need to use the restroom.
Sir, what would you like to order?
It's okay.
I'll go to the restroom.
I'll take a leak.
I'll go too.
Wait,
you two don't go to the same restroom.
Well...
Hello.
Having a blind date.
(Restroom)
A police, over thirty.
I don't know why my mom knew her.
Hello.
But honestly,
I probably won't
get much benefit from this woman.
I did some digging before I came.
With her level and position,
she can earn
ten thousand yuan at most per month.
What's the use?
To put it harshly,
if she were frontline,
died in service,
I could get a compensation
of hundreds of thousands.
Really.
Just a woman without feminine charm,
no fun at all.
(Restroom)
Who did it?
Who beat me?
Where are you?
Don't dare to admit it?
What happened?
Where were you?
Who's in charge?
Took so long.
No one leaves
until I get an explanation.
Who's in charge?
Call him over,
or I'll call the police. Hurry up.
Where's the person in charge?
Call him over. Who hit me?
Get me the surveillance footage now.
Hurry up.
Is this your car?
My friend's.
Sorry for causing trouble.
Thank your friend for me.
It's okay.
I've seen the girl who had dinner
with you today.
Where?
When you first came to the department.
Right at the entrance.
I remember it quite clearly.
I remember she had
a Japanese lunchbox wrapped in cloth
in her hand.
We grew up together.
I can tell that girl really likes you.
Ziwu.
We're just friends.
I wish she thought the same way.
I forgot to warn that scum
to stay away from my restaurant.
After what you did,
he'd never dare come.
I bet he won't even come near
the area.
But anyway,
you shouldn't have beaten him.
Didn't you hear what Little Qian said?
He's trying to exploit women.
Not a chance.
And I turned off the cameras
near the restroom.
Smart move!
He has no idea who beat him.
You didn't see the face of Little Qian.
If I hadn't hit him first,
he would've done it instead.
Right.
Has he been like this?
So violent?
Of course not!
Little Qian has always been
good at learning
and gentle.
He can cook
and paint well.
He was a track and field star.
Total heartthrob!
Really?
Cross my heart.
Let me tell you.
Many people
had crushes on him back then.
(There was a long line of admirers!)
Little Qian.
(If we were taking numbers,)
(I'd be first in line.)
Little Qian, fight for it!
(But he only had eyes for Chen Yumo.)
Because of Chen Yumo,
he fell out with his parents
and went to police academy,
becoming a police.
The most dangerous kind,
criminal police.
After all these years,
he'd chase any lead
about Chen Yumo
until he confirmed it was false.
It's been ten years.
You know he doesn't like you.
Doesn't that hurt you?
It hurts, of course.
But I'm willing to wait.
I'm still young, right?
For someone I love,
I'll take the chance.
I'll grab more drinks.
One.
Already back?
What are you doing?
Little Zhao
rides motorcycles and runs a restaurant.
Where else could I find
such an amazing girl?
I've decided.
I need to earn more money.
One meal cost me half a month's salary.
That won't do.
Can't keep this up.
Where are you going?
Are you sneaking off to see Little Zhao?
Go on!
I'll focus on earning money.
Work hard. Earn big.
(At the department or at home?)
(Zhang Ziwu:
At the department or at home?)
Ziwu.
Lei.
Little Qian's parents
are overseas, right?
I've never heard him call them
once in the dorm.
What a distant family.
But he and Captain Leng...
Honestly, they're kind of similar.
Men of few words, workaholics,
avoid relationships.
Talking to them
is like pulling teeth sometimes.
Can't figure out
what Little Zhao sees in him.
He's handsome!
Little Zhao?
The girl from that restaurant?
How do you know?
She's really into Ye Qian.
Don't get your hopes up.
Something's going on.
Hurry. Tell me!
What is there to tell?
Not promising?
Unrequited love.
How tough.
(Shancheng Community, North Gate)
(Eternal Love)
(China Railway High-speed)
I've booked the room.
I'll pick him up tomorrow noon.
Okay. I'll transfer you the room fee
via WeChat this afternoon.
No need.
He hasn't finished his homework.
It's in the bag.
Tell him to do it, okay?
Xiaoyu, be good, okay?
I will pick you up tomorrow noon.
Alright.
I'm leaving.
Where do you want to go?
Let's go eat.
What do you want to eat?
Anything.
Where's Master?
He took leave.
He took leave?
Where did he go?
He went to Shanghai.
Well, could you give this to him for me?
Thanks.
(Theater Entrance)
Are you a child?
No.
Is this fun?
Yes.
Why are you alone?
Where's Little Qian?
Something holds him up,
so he won't come.
Why didn't you tell me?
If I'd tell you, you wouldn't have come.
Take it.
What for?
I'm leaving.
Wait. You're already here.
We can just watch it together.
About that motorcycle case,
I've wanted to thank you.
You thank me?
Little Qian should be
the one thanking me.
With our relationship,
it doesn't really matter.
It took you a whole month
to recall that?
I've been remembering it.
But my actions got hindered.
Look at my hand.
I'm like a fortune cat.
I can barely manage to eat.
You can barely manage to eat.
But you send me selfies every day.
You fortune cat!
You thank me by inviting me to a movie,
and I bought the tickets?
After the movie,
I'll treat you to dinner.
Not a big deal.
Relax. I'm shopping with my mom.
I'll tell her now.
Since when did I become your mom?
Last time, you sent
Little Qian dumplings.
I lied to him
that my mom made them.
And you told me he accepted them
and really enjoyed them?
He did accept them and eat them.
And he enjoyed them.
Si Yuanlong.
Can you stop telling lies?
Can I trust you to handle things?
Yes! Of course.
Absolutely.
Are you wearing Little Qian's jacket?
He gave them to me.
How is it?
Do I look better than him wearing it?
W-Well...
Talk about that later.
Let's go watch it.
(Have you seen Xiaoyu?)
(Zhang Ziwu: Have you seen Xiaoyu?)
(Leng Qiming: Just had a meal with him.
He's doing homework now.)
(Zhang Ziwu: Have you seen Xiaoyu?)
(Leng Qiming: Just had a meal with him.
He's doing homework now.)
(Zhang Ziwu: Talk to him more.
Don't just stare at him.)
Got a lot of homework?
It's manageable.
I've been swamped lately.
Well...
I know.
Call me if anything's wrong.
Nothing's wrong.
How are you and your mom
getting used to things over there?
Dad, I'm doing homework.
Want ice cream?
Chocolate.
Okay.
I'll buy it.
(Loyalty, Justice, Service, Dedication)
Ye.
- Chief Xu.
- Where's your master?
Went to Shanghai.
Shanghai?
To see his son?
Call him.
Ask him to come back.
Okay.
Don't eat this often.
Too fatty.
I've paid for the room.
I'll send you the money.
- Don't bother.
- Let's go.
Be a good boy.
Let's go.
Bye, Dad.
How have you been?
Had a nice time?
Have you missed me?
Did you bring me a gift?
Of course.
(Adopt With Love, Take Me Home)
How could I forget that?
You guys are doing a charity event?
Have water.
Thank you.
How strong
the sunshine is.
Thanks.
Let's see. What kind of dogs are these?
So cute.
Have some water.
- Hello, this is Jiao Lei.
- Here you go.
What kind of dogs?
Okay, I'll be there.
Are they strays?
(Ye Qian:
Urgent mission. Come back now.)
Little Zhao.
I've got a mission.
I have to go.
What do you mean?
You insisted on watching.
Now you want to leave me here
all by myself?
I'm really sorry.
That's just how my job is.
Please forgive me.
I owe you a meal.
Aren't you off today?
You're not leaving.
I'm going.
Everyone's here?
Three days ago,
within Beicheng County's jurisdiction,
a homicide occurred.
The victim, Wang Xiaole,
lived in Apartment 402,
Building 10 of Shancheng Community,
got murdered in her home.
Beicheng CID requested assistance
from city police department.
And after deliberation
by city police department leadership,
our department and the forensic unit
are assigned to assist.
These two are from Beicheng CID.
Let them brief us on the case.
Just call me Sun.
I'm Zhou.
(Loyalty, Justice, Service, Dedication)
Captain Sun, it's all copied.
Good. I'll brief everyone.
(Photos of Wang Xiaole)
The victim is Wang Xiaole,
33 years old,
a teacher at the Yunxi Health School.
Her parents reported the case.
According to her dad,
around 9 PM on the night of the murder,
he sent her a message.
But he waited until the next morning
and still got no reply.
So he and his wife got anxious
and went straight to her home.
(Photos of Wang Xiaole)
(Wang Xiaole's bedroom)
This is the victim, Wang Xiaole.
(Wang Xiaole's Bedroom)
This is the crime scene,
the bedroom.
(Wang Xiaole's bedroom)
Long, that outfit
looks pretty sharp today.
Double-check it.
Okay.
Are you crazy?
Why are you wearing my jacket?
You gave it to me.
Why can't I wear my own jacket?
When did I give it to you?
That day we had hotpot.
You threw such a nice jacket away?
Quit the nonsense.
I threw this jacket away,
not gave it to you.
(Police)
You did throw it away.
But I asked you
to give it to me if you didn't want it.
I asked you several times.
I thought you were joking.
Joking?
Why would I joke about a nice jacket?
It just had some frays.
I fixed them and it's all good.
Throwing it away is such a waste. Look.
Alright.
Then don't wear it when I do.
Fine. Tell me in advance,
I'll wear a different one.
I don't want to wear the same as you.
Captain Leng.
The primary crime scene
has been fully processed by our team.
Tell me about this community.
Shancheng Community
was built over twenty years ago.
The buildings are old.
Look, over there.
It borders a wooded area.
It's pitch black at night.
We immediately
reviewed all accessible
(Keeping pet in a civilized way)
CCTV footage from the community.
(Keeping pet in a legal way)
At the south gate,
a suspicious person was spotted.
However, his identity
remains unknown.
Fingerprints and footprints
from the hallway surroundings
and living room
have been re-collected.
The entryway mat was taken
by Beicheng CID.
A total of five bloody footprints
were found
on the entryway mat
and in the living room.
Details await further testing.
Zhou.
Based on bloodstain distribution,
it's concentrated near the nightstand.
The blood spatter
shows a high-velocity pattern.
This indicates a powerful impact.
I assumed the suspect
is a young or middle-aged male.
Based on the stroke width,
it was likely written
using a blood-soaked finger.
But no fingerprints were left.
Captain Leng.
Take a look.
Thoughts?
The writing flows smoothly.
The strokes are steady.
And it's in standard script.
What kind of person
writes like this?
Composed
and calm.
Probably well-educated.
After committing such extreme violence,
he still had composure
to write on the wall.
I think he is someone meticulous
and unflappable.
It was likely premeditated.
(Wench)
(Asepsis Testing Room)
(South Gate-03)
(Wench)
(Forensic Unit)
Based on blood coagulation at the scene
and livor mortis,
(Blood details at the crime scene)
the exact time of death was...
The time of death
was between 12 AM
(Blood details at the crime scene)
and 1 AM the next day.
Resulted from acute cerebral hemorrhage.
The victim's skull
(Blood details at the crime scene)
shows a depressed fracture,
matching the corner of the nightstand.
(Blood details at the crime scene)
We can infer
the suspect
grabbed the victim's head
and slammed it against the corner.
Repeated, forceful impacts
ruptured the left pericallosal artery
and the left central artery,
causing massive intracranial bleeding
and victim's death.
Other wounds on the victim's body
were inflicted shortly after death.
(Victim's wound details)
There are seventeen wounds total
on the victim's torso and limbs.
Look.
These seventeen wounds
are straight, sharp,
(Victim's wound details)
and uniform in length.
This requires the suspect
to possess precise control.
Moreover, I noticed
during the cutting,
a downward pressure was applied.
This motion matches
a scalpel user's technique.
No fingerprints were found on scene.
The killer wore gloves
both during the murder
and writing on the wall.
(Blood writing on the crime scene wall)
I compared common types
like cotton, synthetic fiber,
cloth, leather,
and latex gloves.
Only non-absorbent types
can be dipped in blood for writing.
After elimination,
only leather and latex
remain possibilities.
Leather gloves
are typically bulkier than fingers.
When I tried writing in them,
caused by the finger squeezing,
the writing shows breaks or distortions.
Difficult to write words with
uniform strokes on the wall,
let alone the fluidity of the writing
on the crime scene wall.
Leather gloves out.
As for the last possibility,
latex gloves are characterized
by high elasticity,
smooth surface,
and fit closest
to the size of human fingers.
I bought commonly available
latex gloves on the market.
(Blood writing on the crime scene wall)
After testing with blood,
I preliminarily assumed the killer
wore medical latex gloves.
These gloves have talcum powder on them,
which has
a certain adhesive effect on the blood.
This can result in dripping blood trails
(Wretch)
forming below the writing.
(Suspect's shoe printings
left on the crime scene floor)
Around the hallway,
on the entryway mat
and inside the crime scene,
a total of five footprints
were collected.
All are of size 43,
mold-soled sneakers.
The tread pattern shows minimal wear,
indicating the shoes
might be relatively new.
However, because this type of product
is extremely common on the market,
it has little reference value.
Due to the small number
of footprints collected
and their discontinuity,
we can currently only roughly
infer that the suspect is
(Suspect's shoe printings)
a male of medium build.
We cannot infer
more specific physical characteristics.
The Shancheng Community
has cameras only at the main gates
on the north and south sides
for vehicle access.
Those at the side gates
on the east and west,
and between buildings,
are just for show,
not even powered.
Colleagues from Beicheng
had conducted
a preliminary review of the footage.
(Suspicious individual entering/exiting)
The time of this individual
entering and exiting
through the south gate
matches the time of the crime.
Thus, Beicheng CID
identified this person
as the prime suspect.
(Victim's ex-husband entering/exiting)
Okay.
From this image, we can see
he's wearing exactly a pair of
mold-soled sneakers.
(Victim's ex-husband entering/exiting)
This person is the victim's
ex-husband, Wu Da.
Captain Sun's team has confirmed
that Wang Xiaole's boyfriend,
Huang Chong,
was working overtime at the company
that night.
His colleagues can attest to this.
Wang Xiaole's parents also stated
that the two had a good relationship.
Moreover, both are
in their second marriage,
with no financial conflicts.
However,
Wang Xiaole's ex-husband, Wu Da,
was seen entering and exiting
the Shancheng Community
at 9 PM and 10 PM
on the night of the crime.
Wu Da's semen was indeed
found inside the victim.
But there's no evidence
of forced sexual activity at the scene.
All evidence suggests
the sexual encounter was consensual.
They were divorced,
yet they maintained that relationship.
We need to look into it.
Wu Da,
we're here today
to learn more
about Wang Xiaole.
Where did you injure your hand?
I forgot.
Probably bumped into something.
(Admission Letter)
(Surgery, Surgical Nursing)
(Vascular Surgery, Dermatologic Surgery)
(Clinical Oncology)
How did he get so drunk?
He was also like this
during your previous questioning?
Yes.
He was like this.
(Surgery, Surgical Nursing)
It's said that ever since the divorce,
(Vascular Surgery)
he's been drowning his sorrows in drink.
(Clinical Oncology)
He seems unable to accept this reality.
Do you know Wang Xiaole?
My wife...
Ex-wife.
What were you doing
from 12 AM on the 9th
to 1 AM on the 10th?
Drinking.
Where were you drinking?
Specific location.
The flower bed at the north gate
of Shancheng Community.
Can anyone verify that?
Verify?
Verify what?
What exactly happened, Officer?
You went to Wang Xiaole's place
last night, didn't you?
Why did you go there?
I just... We...
I went to get...
Wait, officer.
I'm feeling really unwell.
Can you just tell me what's wrong?
Here.
Xiaole?
♪Replacing the weight of tears
with that of sweat♪
♪Covering the gunshot's sound
with wounds♪
♪No one is born unyielding and strong♪
♪But because someone
always rushes ahead♪
♪To shield us from the storm♪
♪When every extraordinary act
becomes routine♪
♪Just to polish the badge
upon their shoulder♪
♪Like light surging unseen
through the night♪
♪Converging into your form♪
♪Looking up♪
♪Such dazzling glory♪
♪Like hope♪
♪Reaching out its arms♪
♪Cloaked in light♪
♪Alone, they charge ahead♪
♪Traversing♪
♪The battlefield of fate♪