=The Truth=
=Episode 5=
Chen Yumo, a local from Yunxi City.
Ten years ago, you were gang-raped.
Afterward, your whole family moved away.
Five years later,
your parents died in a car accident,
and you returned to Yunxi.
(Dan Qing/Chen Yumo Profile)
You met Huo at the nightclub.
Then you went to the border.
When the rape happened,
you were only 16 years old.
You had a boyfriend.
He was your classmate
at Experimental High School.
His name was Ye Qian.
(And that Ye Qian is now a cop.)
Xiang.
It's our first deal.
Mr. Bao wants to be cautious.
We all understand that.
But if just because
an ex-boyfriend
she barely remembers became a cop
makes you question us,
it makes Mr. Bao's reputation
seem pretty overrated.
You say she doesn't remember her ex?
Then why did he go looking for her
at that hotel you used?
Who says I don't remember him?
I remember him.
I'll remember him till death.
If I hadn't been with him...
Stop beating around the bush.
What do you want?
Prove your sincerity.
Prove she's
not a cop.
Go tell Mr. Bao.
If he doesn't trust me,
we don't have to work together.
This is
unnecessary.
Take Madman with you.
Xiang.
I've got a video here.
- I'd like to share it with you.
- Run? Come back.
Boss.
I know I was wrong.
Please let me go.
You want to die?
Tighter.
Run? Get back here.
Boss!
I know I was wrong.
Please let me go.
Boss, I know I was wrong.
I'll never do it again.
Well done, Dan Qing.
Okay.
Got it.
All four are dead?
You can check for yourself.
They're probably just listed as missing.
As our boss just said,
us meeting like this is fate,
a rare chance.
So how about this?
Let your girlfriend
keep in touch with her ex-boyfriend.
After all, in our line of work,
good relations with the cops can't hurt.
Buried where?
Give me the location.
Xiang.
Send someone unrelated to this location.
Take pictures.
Understood.
Just a moment.
One order of wontons.
Sure.
- Okay.
- No spice.
No chili peppers.
Just a second.
Okay.
Add some greens.
Got it.
Hello?
Where are you with the takeout?
I'm starving.
Bag snatcher!
Move! Get out of the way!
Move!
Looking for trouble, huh?
Stay back!
I'll kill you!
Make way.
Coming through.
What happened?
City CID.
Thanks for your help.
We'll take it from here.
Officers,
they're the ones who snatched my bag.
Alright, come with us.
Take them away.
(Interview Room)
(Ye Qian's Profile)
Dan Qing,
still tailing them?
Yes.
Didn't you grab the keys?
What took you so long?
You could have crawled back by now.
What brings you here?
Quick, come in.
- Where's Little Qian?
- Hotpot delivery?
He went to get the takeout.
If I'd known you were coming,
I wouldn't have told him to go.
Don't flatter yourself.
I am not treating you.
Don't say that.
You've brought so much.
It'd be wasteful
not to finish it, right?
What are you waiting for?
Set it up.
Right away.
Give Little Qian a call.
Ask him where he is.
He's been gone forever.
I won't.
If he knows I'm here,
he'll find an excuse to bolt again.
You call.
I just did.
He didn't answer.
No need to call. He's back.
Dad? Mom?
What a surprise!
Give me that.
Come on in.
Should've told me.
I could've picked you up.
Do we need an appointment?
This is...
Let me introduce you.
This is my good friend, Han Zhao.
And these are my parents.
Hello, ma'am, sir.
Hello.
Long,
where's your roommate?
The tall, slim, fair-skinned one?
He went to get the takeout.
He should be back soon.
Sit down.
Mom, I'll get you a chair.
Sir, have a seat.
Okay.
Long,
how is this place still such a mess?
I need to tidy up for you later.
Please don't tidy up for me.
You did it last time,
and then I couldn't find anything.
Just sit down and enjoy your meal.
Look at you, then look at Ye.
How is he so neat and tidy?
What sauce? Sesame paste?
I'll mix one for you.
Anything's fine.
These foods look so fancy.
I'm so sorry.
We didn't know Long had company.
We wouldn't have come to intrude.
It's fine.
I brought plenty of food.
Let's just eat together.
Han, right?
How old are you?
What do you do?
She owns a restaurant.
A high-end one.
Running a restaurant is no easy job.
It's manageable.
When Long was little,
he wanted to open a restaurant too.
That's quite a coincidence.
Eat.
You have no chopsticks.
I'll get you a pair.
Do your parents misunderstand something?
Clear things up.
Probably not.
Maybe they just think you're pretty.
If they are mistaken,
just deal with it.
I'm totally fine.
I'll hit you.
Just joking.
Here.
Hurry up and text Little Qian.
Ma'am.
Okay.
Sir.
(Si Yuanlong: Little Zhao is here)
(Ye Qian: Then I won't be back for now)
(Ye Qian, Yunxi Police Department,
Wannan Province)
Let's go.
We're so sorry, Han,
to have you drive us home.
Yeah.
It's fine, sir.
It's just a quick drive.
Don't be polite with me.
Long, don't see us off.
Go back.
I'm already here. Let me.
Alright.
You don't get to visit often.
Rest early. Don't stay up late.
Don't worry.
Stop playing
those violent games all day.
Nagging all night.
Just get in the car.
Get in, ma'am.
Little Zhao, sorry for the trouble.
- Bye-bye.
- It's fine.
Okay.
We're leaving now.
WeChat me when you get home.
Got it.
Take care.
Little Qian, they've left.
I'm a bit full, going for a walk.
Come back now, okay?
(Xinbofa Auto Repair)
Excuse me.
Are you the owner?
What's up?
My bike broke.
Can you take a look?
It's leaking oil.
The tank is empty.
Is it easy to fix?
I need to open it up to see.
If it's good,
I can bore the cylinders
and replace the pistons.
If it's serious,
it requires a new block.
How long?
That's hard to say.
Leave me your number.
I'll call you when it's fixed.
I don't have one.
Alright then.
(Maintenance, Protective Film)
Go north
and you'll find an internet cafe.
Come back in three or four hours.
(Route of the crime)
Based on this route,
we can confirm
that He Changchun
is fleeing the province.
We already know
his last known location
was Linshui Township.
Less than 300 kilometers
south of Linshui is the border
between Wannan
and the neighboring province.
Chief Xu is filing a report
with the higher-ups.
Checkpoints are on all major routes
at the provincial border.
Captain Liao is rushing here now.
The roads around Linshui
are very complex.
Manpower and time are both issues.
True.
If we canvass the area
and launch a manhunt,
the efficiency will be low.
If He Changchun senses something
and chooses to flee on foot,
with all the mountains and forests
south of Linshui,
he's a needle in a haystack.
Any news from your friend?
Not yet.
(Manufactured: February 2013)
Yes, I found one.
The ID number is a match.
Go.
You're here.
Here's the auto repair shop address.
Both the engine number and VIN match.
It has those stickers too.
It's that bike.
Thanks.
I'll buy you a meal later.
You guys are working on a Sunday?
Lend me a car, will you?
Doesn't he have one?
That place is far away.
His car would rattle my bones loose.
Sir,
it's been three hours. Is it fixed?
Your...
Your bike is in bad shape.
Can't fix it. Needs parts replaced.
Look,
the piston rings and valve seals.
Both are shot.
I have those here.
But for your crankshaft case,
I don't have one in stock.
J-Just wait a bit.
I'll have one sent over.
From where?
And by whom?
Are there any other auto repair shops
around here besides yours?
Y-Yes.
It's just...
Just a bit further away.
There's one in the next town.
Look, buddy.
W-What are you asking all this for?
Are you fixing it or not?
If you're not getting it fixed,
I'll put it back together.
Just pay the disassembly fee.
(Manufactured: February 2013)
Fix it.
Okay. Wait a moment.
I'll have someone deliver it.
You know, the part is expensive.
D-Don't skip out on the bill.
Hello, Chief Xu.
He Changchun
showed up at an auto repair shop
near Linshui.
Ye and Si Yuanlong
are both heading there.
They're on the way.
How much longer until you arrive?
We're rushing there now.
But with this rain,
we can't drive too fast.
After getting the lead,
we immediately contacted the local CID.
They're on the way to assist.
Okay.
Hurry. As fast as possible.
(Xinbofa Auto Repair)
After him!
Captain Leng, we're at the shop.
He Changchun is driving east.
The owner is out. Get an ambulance.
How's your hand?
(Yunxi Police Department)
Have some water.
Thanks. I was starving.
You're fed and watered?
Let's talk?
This bag is yours, right?
And this knife?
It's mine.
My parents.
Why kill He Hongqing's whole family?
They bullied us.
Explain it in detail.
Okay.
Let me tell you.
That year,
my grandpa was very ill.
He called all his children
to divide the farmland.
- My dad saw his dilemma.
- Little Qian.
He let the others pick first.
I can't open it.
He ended up with the worst plot.
I spent three months
clearing rocks from that land
before planting anything.
The next year,
- during harvest...
- Thanks.
Good thing your tendon wasn't injured.
- Long.
- My uncle, He Shanxiang...
Don't be so reckless next time.
He brought a group to corner my dad
and demanded those five acres back.
They said Grandpa was senile,
so it didn't count.
My dad argued with them,
and they beat him up.
Yet my dad stayed silent
when he came home.
Soon after, he died of anger.
(The irony is,)
(they refused to bury him
in the He family graves.)
I wouldn't stand for it then.
But I still had my mom.
She struggled to keep
the family together and raise me.
But then,
they came to our place
on Chinese New Year's Eve
(and smashed everything they could.)
(Mom fainted on the spot.)
(At the hospital, they found cancer.)
This year,
my uncle's family
joined the village co-op
for land transfers.
They brought a land lease contract
to the hospital
to trick my mom into signing.
They harassed her over and over.
Eventually, my mom
couldn't take it and died.
The doctor said that
had she not been so pressed,
she might've lived another year or two.
I'm the youngest in our generation.
They always bullied me growing up.
I'd run home crying,
and my dad would say,
"They're family."
"They're fond of you
and playing with you."
My dad never fought back.
He endured it his whole life
until he was gone.
My mom endured it too,
and now she's gone too.
Now it's just me left.
I wanted to fight back.
Just this once.
Officer.
Do you think I was wrong?
Of course you were wrong.
Why did you hurt more people?
That traffic cop
suspected the motorcycle wasn't mine.
He pressed me too hard. I had no choice.
The woman at the convenience store
scrolled on her phone.
She saw the news
and recognized me.
And the auto repair shop owner
was calling the police.
So I hurt him.
What about Xu Gang?
Who's Xu Gang?
The motorcycle driver.
You stole his bike
and then killed him.
Remember now?
I didn't know him.
(I didn't mean to kill him.)
(But he fought me desperately)
(over a motorcycle.)
(I panicked a bit.)
(They were like)
(a cornfield blocking my path.)
Whether I snapped them or chopped them,
I had to get through.
You killed He Hongqing's whole family.
Why did you spare the child?
I'm human,
not a monster.
Besides,
that kid hadn't done anything wrong.
After all this,
you think your parents' deaths
were entirely your uncle's fault.
You think killing him was justified.
If we hadn't caught you,
were you going
to let your nephew settle that score
when he grew up?
To turn him into the next you?
As you said,
that kid did nothing wrong.
The adults messed up.
Why make a kid pay the price?
How are you any better than your uncle?
Right.
So I'm confessing everything now
and cooperating fully.
I'm cooperating.
I wasn't trying to run.
My parents lived in that village
most of their lives
but never saw the real sea.
I wanted to take them to see it.
The sea's better,
better than suffering
in the ancestral grave.
Right?
Well? Want some more?
No, I'm full.
That's enough.
We'll talk again next time, okay?
Got it all down?
Yes.
Officer.
Thank you.
I've kept these things bottled up
and never told anyone.
(Your grievances deserved to be heard,)
(but your crimes)
(must face judgment.)
Can I ask a favor?
I didn't make it to the sea.
My parents...
Tired?
No.
Let me drive. You can take a break.
It's fine.
Why'd you say yes to He Changchun?
Didn't think much about it.
Just hoped it might
plant some kindness in him.
Have you contacted
your parents recently?
Filial piety
is the foundation of all virtues.
Call them more often, just to check in.
Okay.
Master,
I have a classmate in the States.
I heard they've developed a new drug
for Alzheimer's.
If you ever need it,
I'll have it brought for you.
Quite expensive, right?
No. It's on me.
How dutiful.
In the end,
we're all just a handful of ashes.
Scattered by the wind.
Cast into the sea,
without a trace left behind.
Why be so stubborn while alive?
We all meet the same end.
Master.
Why make me your apprentice?
Then why did you become a cop?
I know you can't let it go.
And I'm not asking you to.
You're still young.
Life ahead is long.
Don't trap yourself.
Master.
Spend more time with Xiaoyu
when you can.
When he's around,
you're genuinely happy.
A father's faults
are as numerous as the stars.
But his virtues?
Like the sun.
When it rises,
the stars all vanish.
♪Replacing the weight of tears
with that of sweat♪
♪Covering the gunshot's sound
with wounds♪
♪No one is born unyielding and strong♪
♪But because someone
always rushes ahead♪
♪To shield us from the storm♪
♪When every extraordinary act
becomes routine♪
♪Just to polish the badge
upon their shoulder♪
♪Like light surging unseen
through the night♪
♪Converging into your form♪
♪Looking up♪
♪Such dazzling glory♪
♪Like hope♪
♪Reaching out its arms♪
♪Cloaked in light♪
♪Alone, they charge ahead♪
♪Traversing♪
♪The battlefield of fate♪