=The Truth=
=Episode 3=
Jiang Lianhong, take a look.
I said she looked like...
He Jie.
You mean
the He Jie you raped 20 years ago?
What's He Jie's
connection to Jiang Honghai?
I've told you everything I know.
Go arrest him.
Why do you keep questioning me?
Then let's start with this.
Who is this?
It's too blurry. I can't see clearly.
What?
You forgot who you ate with that day?
Jiang Han.
Does he know Jiang Honghai too?
We're from the same village.
He's a mason.
He referred all the masons.
Why didn't you mention it earlier?
I didn't know he was involved in this.
Check this guy out.
What's Jiang Honghai's
connection to the rape case
22 years ago?
That day, a lot of police
came to my place.
All there to arrest me.
They said I got a young girl
pregnant.
But I never did it.
I didn't even know her.
But that kid described everything
about me clearly.
She even had my underwear.
I only found out later
that Honghai was behind that.
It was all planned.
You're saying
Jiang Honghai and He Jie
colluded to frame you?
Not just them.
Honghai's dad too.
And my own dad.
Then why would the victim
falsely accuse you?
Honghai was 25 that year.
He got her pregnant
and secretly took her
to get an abortion.
He Jie's parents called the police.
Honghai couldn't go to jail.
So he and He Jie
threw the blame on me
while his dad came to see my dad.
His dad was a village official.
He turned everyone against me.
Even the police were fooled.
My family couldn't fight them.
Later, he gave us 20,000 yuan
and an acre of land.
(My dad told me...)
"Son,
just admit it."
She's all settled in.
Don't worry.
We almost caught him.
I should've anticipated his next move.
His target has been Chen Xiaomeng.
Calm down.
How can I calm down?
He almost succeeded.
He's a murderer, a rapist.
As I've already said,
we've sent people
to protect Chen Xiaomeng.
Let's head back.
Captain Leng might have new leads.
Let's go. I'll drive.
Let's go.
Captain Leng.
We got something.
Jiang Han, 40 years old,
no prior record.
He also grew up in the village.
He's around the same age
as Jiang Lianhong.
He teaches at a mason training school
and helps young villagers find work.
Bring Jiang Han in immediately.
See if we can get
new leads from him.
Focus on finding Jiang Honghai.
Yes, sir. I'm on it.
(Ye Qian: Chen Xiaomeng is safe.)
Should be here.
Jiang Han?
City Police Department.
A few questions.
I'm just a trainer.
Conditions in our village aren't good.
Many young guys rely on this skill
to make a living.
(Yunxi Police)
Did you refer Jiang Lianhong too?
Jiang Lianhong?
We do manual labor,
but jobs aren't easy to find now.
But he got lucky.
Met some good people.
Someone pulled strings
to pay his training fees.
Later on,
they even gave him jobs
on construction sites.
Who was that person?
Jiang Honghai.
His family used to be
in the renovation business.
They're pretty well-off.
His dad used to be a village official.
Most of the fishponds
in our village belong to his family.
Right.
Honghai has this habit.
He loves making soup
with live brood fish.
Says it's nourishing.
He has it every single day.
So, he always keeps
a fish tank where he lives.
Every few days,
he has his family
deliver fresh brood fish to him.
You may not know.
Brood fish are really expensive.
Luckily, his family has fishponds.
Or who could've afforded that?
(Yunxi Police)
On May 25th,
where were you
between 10 PM and midnight?
May 25th?
Let me think.
That night,
I was drinking at a restaurant.
Who were you drinking with?
Jiang Lianhong and Jiang Honghai.
But Jiang Honghai can't hold his liquor.
He was clamoring to leave before 11 PM.
I drank for a bit longer
and then left too.
Didn't pay attention to the exact time.
Did you see Jiang Honghai again
after that?
No.
Besides home and construction sites,
does Jiang Honghai
have any other places to stay?
Jiang Honghai is a strange one.
He's used to keeping to himself.
But I have a storage warehouse.
A year ago, he asked me for its key
and wanted to keep
construction equipment there.
He hasn't returned the key yet.
Where is that warehouse?
28, North Xinyuan Lane.
In the abandoned place
by the noodle shop.
We got something.
Jiang Honghai also drank
with them that night.
And he left first.
Wang Tong,
share the address.
Yes.
Let's go.
Master,
this building's abandoned.
Lights on the second floor.
Target is likely there.
Standard procedure.
Wang Tong.
- You take point.
- Okay.
You provide backup.
We secure the perimeter.
Get down.
Don't move.
Jiang Lianhong wanted to cover for you
and take the blame for you.
Did you know that?
He...
he might have been
doing it for his dad.
(Dual usage of devices
is strictly prohibited)
Why protect Jiang Honghai?
My dad has uremia.
He needs dialysis.
I had no choice.
Once, when we were drunk,
he told me,
"Lianhong,
if anything ever happens to you,
I'll take care of your dad
until the end."
Well,
my life is worthless.
Whether I live or die doesn't matter.
Back then, you seduced He Jie
and got her pregnant at just 13.
After her parents found out,
you forced her to commit perjury
and pinned all the blame
on Jiang Lianhong.
Now you've committed these three crimes.
You've destroyed five families.
(Dual usage of devices
is strictly prohibited)
Why target them?
Jiang Honghai,
you won't get away this time.
No one can take the fall for you.
You reap what you sow.
The law will get you.
(Jiang Honghai finally pleaded guilty
in the face of evidence.)
(For the case of his false accusation
against Jiang Lianhong 22 years ago,)
(Yunxi Police Department has established
a task force for further investigation.)
Qian.
We've finally delivered justice
for the victims.
But that's far from enough.
Ye Qian,
you need to learn to channel that energy
in the right direction.
So the suffering before
won't have been in vain.
Understood, master.
Keep it up.
Here, have some jasmine tea.
It'll cool you down.
We got him.
Did he say why?
He chose victims randomly.
The reason was not you.
It wasn't your fault.
He will face severe punishment.
Thank you.
(Jiang Honghai was the true culprit)
(of Jiang Lianhong's rape case
22 years ago.)
(Jiang Honghai confessed to all crimes
and was sentenced to life imprisonment,)
(deprived of political rights for life.
The old case is now cleared.)
(No-Name Diner)
(Yunxi Police Department
Field Staff's Designated Canteen)
(No-Name Diner)
Liu.
Coming.
Give me a hand.
Lei,
you're back.
You guys done eating?
Yes.
Alright.
Take care now.
Bye.
Take care.
Here.
Shan,
lend a hand.
Shan, give us a hand here.
Lei, you're back.
Gao.
Haven't seen you here in ages.
That's true.
Sit down.
Okay.
Alright. Go ahead.
- Enjoy your food.
- Okay.
We will.
Bye.
Haisheng,
pulling overtime again?
Lei, you're back.
Why'd you buy so much salt again?
- We still have some.
- It was on sale.
Why is it so crowded today?
Yang from Propaganda retired.
It's a goodbye dinner.
That explains the crowd.
Jing.
Jing, pork chop noodles for me.
Coming right up.
Okay. Thanks.
You have pork chop noodles now?
With your belly? Forget about it.
Then I'll go keep Yang company.
Go ahead.
Yang,
you're retiring.
Why come to the canteen
instead of eating out?
Ever since your wife
took over this designated canteen,
the food's been tastier
than any restaurant.
- Thanks.
- All done?
Jing, we're finished.
Back to the station.
Okay.
Go ahead.
Thanks, Jing.
Take care.
Okay.
Let's go.
Stay put.
Don't move around, got it?
Chang, how's the homework going?
Not bad.
Your handwriting keeps getting better.
Have some water.
Jing.
You're here, He.
Sorry to bother you.
It's okay. Chang got straight
to his homework.
Really?
Your mother-in-law?
Did she get admitted?
Don't even ask.
Did you say thank you to Ms. Jing?
Thank you, Ms. Jing.
You're welcome.
We'll head off now.
Say goodbye.
- Bye, Ms. Jing.
- Bye.
- Take care.
(No-Name Diner)
That's a northeastern accent.
Braised pork chop noodles
for table three.
- You're here.
- You look busy.
Take a seat.
Shan, two fried noodles, please.
Coming.
Don't move it.
It's too heavy. Let me do it.
It's fine.
Be careful.
Shan,
two fried noodles here.
Right away.
(Guotai North Street Station)
Jing,
is my soup ready?
Been ready.
I'll get it for you, Ziwu.
Are you eating here
or taking it to go?
To go.
Okay.
Here.
Is it hot?
Smells great.
Lunchbox.
Jing.
Qiming.
One vegetable fried rice, please.
Got it.
- Right away.
- Go ahead.
Let me.
Alright, you two find a seat then.
Jing, I'm off.
Take care.
(Rye Bread)
(Leng Xingguo)
(First Prize)
(Provincial Model Police Officer)
Leng.
Your father took his evening meds.
I didn't give him
the supplements.
He finished
all the supplements
you put in the pill box.
Those bottles are colorful
with foreign writing.
Couldn't read it.
So I didn't touch them.
I'll handle it.
Okay.
I need to tell you,
your father had another episode
this afternoon.
After his nap,
he was watching TV just fine,
and then he suddenly said
he wanted to call
some old colleagues from way back.
I didn't dare stop him.
He even got out
the phone book.
Luckily, they were landline numbers.
Probably those old colleagues
don't use landlines anymore.
He didn't get through.
I just wanted to let you know.
Okay.
I'm leaving now.
Okay, take care.
(Rye Bread)
(Rizhixing Travel)
(Zhantong Taxi Company)
(Xi A D02336)
(Did you see her around 7 PM)
(on June 20th?)
(She got in my car back then)
(and told me to detour a bit)
(before we reached a place.)
(But she didn't get out.)
(She got out at a hotel later.)
Hello.
Excuse me,
is there a Chen Yumo here?
(Solo Party.K)
Come on, have a drink with me.
Another round.
Come on.
Another one.
Hello, you two.
Right away.
You shouldn't have brought
your wife here.
We can't let loose.
I thought we were here
for business today.
Huo, famous across the Southwest,
is actually henpecked?
If this gets out,
no one in our circle will believe it.
And from what I know,
your wife should be
the young lady
of the Nanbang family, right?
Was that on purpose?
Don't bring up my ex-wife again.
Right, ex-wife.
So you lost your wife's family backing
and couldn't operate there anymore?
That's why you want to move
into the Wannan market?
The crackdowns over there
Have gotten stricter these years.
Business is tough.
Plus, the market for the old goods
is shrinking.
I have to switch things up.
It's on me.
You don't trust us?
Huo, your reputation
has always been well-known.
But this is our first time
working together after all.
Caution is the parent of safety.
We have our own principles.
Business is business.
Flesh
is something we don't touch.
So, you won't give me any face?
I don't care about your rules.
This is Wannan.
If you want to get things done here,
you must play by our rules.
You're not cops, are you?
Old-timer,
you've watched too many movies.
What era is this?
You'll be ousted like this.
Not touching flesh
doesn't make us cops, right?
Truly sharp-tongued.
You make it sound like
I'm pushing you too hard.
Since you won't give me any face,
then there's no point
in working together.
Sister-in-law,
you make things complicated.
What's wrong with using it?
I'll use.
What did you just call me?
Sister-in-law.
What's our rule?
We don't touch flesh.
Look at you.
You've never quit, have you?
Breaking the rule knowingly.
Want out?
But they were too arrogant.
My apologies
for the drama.
Since Mr. Bao doesn't want to cooperate,
then
we'll take our leave.
Don't touch me.
We smashed up your place twice in a row.
My apologies.
Call Gui.
(I miss you so much at Solo)
You're here.
Thanks.
Have a seat.
Why treat me again?
You really don't have to.
I looked for the person
you asked me to find.
At least within Yunxi City,
I couldn't find any trace of her.
Okay, thanks.
Then, please just keep an eye out
for me whenever you can.
(Ye Qian's friend)
(Lawyer, Wannan Law Firm)
Who is Chen Yumo to you,
that you'd go this far?
Someone very important to me.
Let's eat.
Waiter, order please.
Huo and Qing, you're here.
Our boss
has arranged this place for you.
For the time being,
you can stay here peacefully.
Here are the keys.
If you need anything,
just tell me. I'm Qiang.
Don't stand on ceremony at all.
The decorations here
aren't antiques
or cultural relics, are they?
Coming from a small town,
we tend to be a bit clumsy.
We can't risk breaking
anything we can't afford.
Qing, you're joking.
With the goods you possess,
you could buy anything.
But we need the channels to cash them.
That's exactly why we came
to find your boss' boss
for cooperation.
Don't worry about that.
The place might be a bit old,
but everything inside is new.
New wine in old bottles.
Mr. Bao sure knows
how to keep up
appearances and substance.
(Provincial Narcotics Division)
Currently,
Huo's gang has made contact
with Bao Hei's side.
They've moved into the place
arranged by Bao Hei.
(Huo, gang leader)
(Bao Hei, the top crime boss in Wannan)
It's No. 4, Dongshan Road, Yunxi City.
(Bao Hei controls nearly
all illegal operations in Wannan.)
(Deputy Director Zhao)
Our people are in position
(Provincial Narcotics Division)
around the area
to closely monitor their movements.
(Deputy Commander Lin,
Provincial Narcotics Division)
(Huo's Gang: Dan Qing, Madman, Liu Zhua)
Huo's gang is the third-largest supplier
(of new drugs
along the southwest border.)
According to our CI,
(Bao Hei)
Bao Hei controls
more than 80% of Wannan's
(meth sales channels.)
For the two gangs' cooperation,
given what we know now,
their mutual trust
is only a matter of time.
(Liuhe City)
(Car Wash)
(Car Wash, Water Refill, Free Parking)
(Traffic police)
Boss, one bowl of oil-mixed noodles.
Sure.
Over there!
Hurry up!
Where did he go?
Over there!
Hurry up!
Coming!
Look!
Hurry!
(Senior Activity Room)
Stop.
Driver's license
and vehicle registration.
(Welcome. Laikeshi Eatery)
(Police)
- Captain Leng.
Captain Leng.
The body was found here.
There are cut marks
on the victim's neck.
He bled out.
Given the bloodstains
and blood volume at the scene,
the carotid artery was likely lacerated.
Rigor mortis is complete.
The time of death was over 12 hours ago.
♪Replacing the weight of tears
with that of sweat♪
♪Covering the gunshot's sound
with wounds♪
♪No one is born unyielding and strong♪
♪But because someone
always rushes ahead♪
♪To shield us from the storm♪
♪When every extraordinary act
becomes routine♪
♪Just to polish the badge
upon their shoulder♪
♪Like light surging unseen
through the night♪
♪Converging into your form♪
♪Looking up♪
♪Such dazzling glory♪
♪Like hope♪
♪Reaching out its arms♪
♪Cloaked in light♪
♪Alone, they charge ahead♪
♪Traversing♪
♪The battlefield of fate♪