It's already two hours past 6:00.
She probably forgot about it.
Let's go.
Yes, Your Highness.
What if she didn't forget?
What if something happened to her?
-Pardon?
-I mean, think about it.
My face is hard to forget.
I guess, I have no choice but to wait,
for such is my generosity.
Did you not say she treated you
like you were a mad slave?
She must have fled after realizing
she'd get a punishment, not a reward.
If you'll excuse me,
I must relieve myself.
…one of the few blessings I was born with.
Poverty, misery, sadness and tears.
There's no punishment.
I just wanted to give you these.
I hoped these might bring
a little fortune into your life,
when you were born
into nothing but misfortune.
Dae-chu, make haste.
Let us go now.
If I am no longer allowed
to live a woman's life…
If tonight is my last chance…
Of all times,
and
of all people…
What took you so long?
Do you have any idea
how long I've been waiting--
That…
That would be my reward.
Your Highness.
Why is your face red?
I just got…
robbed now.
What did they steal?
Well…
It's…
Did you see the bandit's face?
How did he look?
Comely.
Comely…
What? He's comely?
We must find him.
I must have lost my mind.
Why did I do that?
That was ridiculous, even to me.
He must be utterly dumbfounded.
I must go back and explain.
Did he leave?
What do I do?
After tonight,
we won't get to see each other again.
This is why they say
nothing good ever happens at night.
Where did she go?
Oh, dear. It's getting late.
It's the curfew hour!
Close the gates!
But why…
You.
I will catch you no matter what.
Your Highness.
I looked everywhere, but found no one.
It's past the curfew hour.
You must return to the palace.
Let us go back for now.
Yes, Your Highness.
Right, I almost forgot.
The grains are missing?
It wasn't us. It's the work of a thief.
-What?
-Look.
They stole the grains
and left this drawing.
This insolent little…
Gil-dong is truly impressive.
Who's there?
It is curfew.
Present your pass.
Officer Park?
It's me.
It's you, Eun-jo.
Did you see a man wearing black just now?
Only a glimpse.
I was looking for my shoes.
What's the matter?
Right. The curfew pass.
Oh, never mind.
It's just us.
Security is especially tight today.
This is just between you and me.
Whoever has the Baekjeong mask
is Gil-dong.
Oh.
Did Officer Kang Yun-bok find that out?
No, it's…
Well, you don't know him.
He's a newly appointed aide.
He's a pale, well-groomed man.
Oh, I see.
He suspects
those spreading rumors about Gil-dong.
And one of the suspects was questioned.
Who was that?
She's called Lady Dong-ju.
You must know her too.
If I'd come here as Gil-dong, as usual,
I would've been caught.
Ma'am.
You're here.
Why does my baby struggle to fall asleep?
It must be due to malnutrition.
Let me take a look.
This was found in your coat.
I brought the silk shoes.
Why run away?
He's a thief. Of course he ran away.
No.
I'm not talking about the man.
I'm talking about this woman.
Around 8:00 tomorrow morning,
assemble all the court ladies,
including the head court lady.
I will now receive remonstrance.
Let us begin.
By Your Majesty's great wisdom and virtue,
the realm prospers in peace day by day.
It is all thanks to your devoted service.
May Your Majesty take good care
of your royal health
and continue to watch over the realm.
I shall bear it in mind.
Why don't we save the daily praises
for tomorrow
and talk about something more interesting?
I'm so bored here in the palace.
I want to hear about the world out there.
Over the past year,
the storehouses of officials,
including my own, have been robbed.
And apparently,
this thief pretends to be
a righteous outlaw.
There was such an incident?
We must catch the thief.
There is no need
to fuss over some petty thief.
Stories like that have always been around.
It seems like
all of you should be careful.
What do you mean, if I may ask?
The great thief, Im Kkeok-jeong
did not only cut open rice sacks
but also corrupt officials.
What is the name of the thief?
Yes, Your Majesty.
He is known as "the friend on the road,"
and his name is Gil-dong.
Are you sure it isn't
"the poop on the road"?
"Poop"?
The censors' remonstrances are becoming
more and more flattering.
I liked it though.
Do you not like it?
They're all lies.
They're worse than Hong Min-jik.
Chief Censor Hong Min-jik, say that again.
Altering the Sillok annals
is unprecedented in history.
Punishing them based solely on the appeal
would bring great misfortune
upon Your Majesty in the future.
Why don't you offer
your remonstrance as well?
Punishing immoral writings
is right and necessary.
Your Majesty
made the right decision.
Is that so?
Do you miss Hong Min-jik,
Your Majesty?
He may not be to my liking,
but at least he was sincere.
What do you mean?
There's sincerity in here too.
Is that so?
Let me see
where the sincerity is.
Father, are you leaving
the palace already?
I need to meet Min-jik.
Look.
If you don't want it, give it.
I'm cooling it down.
We could go to my house
if you don't like courtesans' house.
This is my bribe.
Please take good care of Eun-jo.
She does not take after you.
She's not soft.
She may seem tender,
but she's strong.
Let it be said that this marriage
was solely my own desire.
My desire to live in comfort
under the protection of a powerful family.
I apologize.
What are you apologizing for?
I always feel like I owe you.
You're funny.
Right. I will send the wedding gifts back.
Please take them. They're for the girl.
They would only be
a burden to my daughter.
You paid a bride price worth a house.
Just how hard do you want
to work my daughter?
You make me ashamed of myself, as always.
Is there a reason why
you came to see me?
No.
I just wanted to say hello.
You've been frowning all day long.
What's the matter?
Oh.
I was just thinking
about the book I read yesterday.
What is it about?
I don't know how to read, so tell me.
So, the story is…
about a woman.
The Grand Prince has summoned us.
-Will he tell us stories again?
-About his achievements?
-Me!
You there.
If the woman kissed first,
it must be love.
Love?
No, it was the first time we met.
So it was love at first sight.
Well, I do have the looks for it.
So the woman in the book
fell in love with the man.
What? No!
Then why did she run away?
Because she was startled
by what she had done.
And the next thing she knew,
she'd already run away.
Clearly, she just tested the water
and ran off.
If it's love at first sight,
why would she run away?
If she had run off with him,
that would be love.
Why do you think she ran away?
Maybe she realized
the water she tested was too lukewarm.
It happens.
She kissed him, full of anticipation.
She expected butterflies
and sparks and all that.
But no.
All she felt was the cold breath
coming from his nose.
That's when she started
feeling uncomfortable.
Don't answer my questions from now on.
-Why?
-I told you not to ask questions too.
Goodness. Then why did she even kiss him?
She is dying to know that herself.
But no matter how hard she thinks,
she can't find the answer.
That's when you use
your heart to understand.
Heart?
Love is like that.
You can never understand it
with your head.
No, it's not love.
It shouldn't be love.
She's engaged.
I know it's just a story,
but what a bad woman.
She should be punished for what she did.
Right?
Of course.
A few lashes wouldn't be
nearly enough, would they?
May I?
Though she kissed him for love,
it may have been a forbidden love
that could never be fulfilled.
Forbidden?
That kind of love
is bound to be deep and intense.
Like a noble lady and a slave.
A mistress and a slave?
A slave.
Slave boy!
Boy. He's my slave boy.
It is true that she thinks I'm a slave.
Is that why she thought
it was forbidden love?
Let me ask you a question.
If that slave
turns out to be a noble man…
or even a Grand Prince…
You always respond in the same way.
Should I take it
as a good sign or a bad sign?
About the slave talk earlier…
Were you referring to your friend?
I mean, that's what I'm thinking.
I don't have a friend.
Of course it was me.
So what was stolen from you yesterday
was a kiss?
I will go to the constabulary
on my own from here.
What about me?
I mean, that's what I'm thinking.
You have a very important thing to do.
My beautiful face
makes the fabric look dull. Doesn't it?
Are you sure it is not because
of the dark cloud hanging over your face?
What is it? What's bothering you now?
I don't know. Everything.
Everything is bothering me.
And this woman here will be my concubine.
No, maybe you already are.
Wait here. I will go
and have them all changed.
Don't bother.
I don't have the courage to defy the fate
my brother has set for me.
What?
I will go with this.
Eventually, it will grow on me.
And eventually, it will look pretty to me.
Madam, the silk dress
I had tailored the other day…
I will come back later.
I don't want to make you uncomfortable.
Can I speak with you briefly?
Could you leave us alone?
Yes, my lady.
I just got my new wig.
If you could pull it gently,
that would be great.
Did you just say "support"?
Yes, that is what I said.
I would like to support both my husband
and the love between you two.
From what I was taught,
that is a wife's virtue.
Who taught you that was a virtue?
Your father or your mother?
I lost both my parents when I was five.
I learned about the virtue
from a book.
From a book?
So you have no intention
of slapping my face
or pulling my hair?
Slap what?
Look, Young Master.
I've been a courtesan for ten years,
and I've never seen a wife
who wants to befriend a concubine.
Oh, dear.
So my fiancée has such a big heart
that she finds good in everything,
even in her enemies.
You can call off the wedding if you want,
but from now on, do not use me
for your silly little games.
Why is No-eul so upset?
Because the one who should be upset
chose compassion.
Pleading might work better
on my big-hearted fiancée than bullying.
Dropped! You'll get a penalty.
You can't hit even a single shot.
I thought your father was in the military.
You're no better yourself.
My family has produced
great scholars for generations.
Brushes are our swords.
But then again, look what happened
to your father with his sharp tongue.
What did you just say?
My sister, Eun-jo,
would have hit them all.
What?
How dare you compare
a concubine's daughter to us?
Enough with that.
But he started it.
When Eun-jo was little,
she played with bows instead of dolls.
She's twice as good an archer as you.
She's just a woman. Stop bluffing.
-Want a bet?
-Sure!
You grown-up men
are acting like little boys.
What are you betting?
Just like love,
fights are meant to be encouraged.
-Your Highness.
-Hello.
I received your message.
-So, Gil-dong robbed again?
-Yes, Your Highness.
By the way,
-is Your Highness unaccompanied?
-Oh, Dae-chu?
Has anyone seen this woman?
I must find this woman!
Only then can I return home!
Dae-chu is looking for silk shoes.
Do you fancy silk shoes?
Well, they have
lovely colors and patterns.
But most of all,
they have a lovely personality.
Silk shoes have a lovely personality?
It's a human.
And everything about them is lovely,
so it must be a woman.
Why don't you stop
investigating my business
and investigate the theft instead?
-Is this the drawing Gil-dong left?
-Yes, Your Highness.
There's no consistency whatsoever
in the items he steals.
Indeed, Your Highness.
Why seaweed?
I wonder if his wife
gave birth or something.
-You're here.
-Did you call for me?
On the night Gil-dong stole the seaweed,
Officer Park saw a suspicious man.
Is that so?
I'm not sure if it was Gil-dong,
but it was a very nimble man.
Actually, Eun-jo must have seen him
better than me.
-Physician Hong was there too?
-Yes.
Do you know the physician?
A woman's corpse is supposed to be
examined by a female physician.
So whenever we lack female officers,
we get help from Physician Hong.
Where is that physician now?
Eun-jo!
Young Master?
What is the matter?
I need you to follow me somewhere.
-A bet?
-Yes.
You just need to hit this apple here.
Are you sure you have the time for this?
You have
a civil service examination to pass.
Do you hang out with those men every day?
They're the only ones who hang out with me
since our family's fallen.
And now, we're like family.
I'll win the bet for you,
if you promise me one thing.
That concubine's daughter
looks familiar somehow.
How unpleasant.
She doesn't know her place
and acts like his sister.
How annoying.
Didn't she refuse to do it at first?
Why did she change her mind?
-Because I agreed to promise one thing.
-A promise?
I agreed to stop hanging out with you two
if she wins.
Is that so?
You.
Do you really not know me?
You look strangely familiar.
Well, I don't think we have met before.
Can I start now?
Wait.
We should change the rules.
You raised the stakes.
Pardon?
If you made your brother
promise something so serious,
you need to risk something too.
Why don't you stand there
instead of the target?
-Jae-i.
-What?
Do you not want to?
What's the matter?
Are you upset?
Not yet.
Go stand there.
You can do it, right?
Eun-jo.
Please.
Please…
I only meant for him
to focus on his studies until the exam.
If this is because
of what I asked him to promise me,
please punish me instead.
I am punishing you.
Does it look like
I'm punishing Dae-il now?
The more Dae-il shivers in fear,
the more your hands tremble.
I'm punishing the right person.
Why would you…
go to such lengths?
It's disgusting to see
a lowly concubine's daughter
acting like his sister.
You're a concubine's child.
It's against propriety and order.
I did not try to act like his sister.
I simply followed my heart.
If my heart itself
is against propriety and order,
I apologize.
Of course.
A woman can't shoot an arrow.
It was all a bluff.
What?
I received my punishment,
so please honor your promise.
Well, this is bad.
I bet my favorite waist sash on this.
You can tie it again.
Did you shoot a flying sparrow?
Well done! You hit a target
that was smaller and farther away.
It's a perfect victory.
My word.
It pierced right through the heart.
Your future sister-in-law
has quite the talent.
Sister-in-law?
Did you not know?
She will be your brother's concubine.
Lord Im Sa-hyeong's second son?
Why are you saying this now?
I told you, they're like my family.
He's our brother-in-law, to be precise.
To be really precise,
he'd be my grandson-in-law.
This is getting messy.
Why are all those people gathered there?
Go ahead without me.
I must tend
to Chief Censor's wife by 2:00.
Nothing's been caught,
other than the Baekjeong mask.
Until the investigation quietens down,
I will have to keep myself
from being nosy.
Right, I forgot about that.
Oh?
Your Highness, just now…
Is the female physician here?
Your Majesty.
Mother. What brings you here?
Are you Officer Kang Yun-bok?
Yes, Your Majesty.
If I ever set foot here again,
it will be with an order for your arrest.
You may leave now.
Why did you refuse
Chief Censor's daughter?
She was unsightly.
You do not belong at the constabulary.
Playing officer is
my little hobby
that even his Majesty has allowed.
When will you stop
living like a scoundrel?
A scoundrel.
An idler. A shameless wretch.
Not anybody can be called these.
Only I, a Grand Prince…
How much more…
How much more disappointment
must I endure?
There will be no more disappointment
so long as you place
no expectations upon me.
You…
You are…
Her Majesty seemed quite upset.
Shouldn't you do something?
Nothing.
Keep your brilliance
hidden from the world.
Keep yourself from my sight,
and do nothing.
I will do nothing.
Your Highness is especially cold
to Her Majesty.
It's good for her that I'm a bad son.
Don't take what Her Majesty said earlier
too much to heart.
Her Majesty was merely letting off steam.
I'm sorry you had to hear that.
It is nothing, Your Highness.
This waiting is getting tedious.
Let me go and meet Physician Hong myself.
My lady.
Are you looking at it?
Why? Is it really that interesting?
Why would anyone read this?
I know he will be my husband,
but I really cannot understand
the appeal of this.
Oh, dear. That's intense.
Could you turn the page?
I hear Gil-dong is a Baekjeong.
Gil-dong?
I want to get out.
Hey, move. Make way.
This man is full of charm.
You speak as if you can see
his face behind the mask.
Yes, I can see it.
I can see his heart, not his face.
SEEKING THIS MAN
Who is this man?
"Name, unknown."
"Notable remarks, a dullard."
"Fusses over cold water
and says it's like a thunderbolt."
"Disrespectful, regardless of company."
Enough reading for now, my lady.
Let us go.
-We must stop by the Hyeminseo.
-Sure.
Goodbye.
I thought you might be hungry,
so I bought these on my way.
You should call the patients over.
I bought enough to share.
I know you used the snacks
as an excuse to wander around the market.
You must conduct yourself properly.
That is not…
No talking back.
You must return home before sunset.
Yes, Father.
Oh, a dullard.
Why do you look at me, Your Highness?
Pardon me.
See? She's talking to you.
May I help you?
By any chance,
is the man next to you a dullard?
I can hear you.
You are mistaken.
-He is--
-I'm an aide.
I apologize.
You look like a dullard
someone is looking for,
so I asked.
Don't worry.
Surprisingly, it isn't my first time
being called a dullard.
Well, then, if you'll excuse me…
Watch out.
By the way,
what was Physician Hong
doing there late at night?
Women don't usually go out
at such a late hour.
Well, you may ask her yourself.
Look, Jeom-baek.
Where is Physician Hong?
Eun-jo is off duty today.
Oh, dear. Where would she be now?
Whenever she's off duty,
she goes around seeing patients.
So we do not know.
We can't see her today either?
It is really hard to meet this physician.
Your Highness.
These are the people
who have visited the widow.
"Lady next door, lady across the road,
lady from the house behind,
lady two doors down,
female shaman, female physician."
Were there any male visitors?
No, Your Highness.
She didn't leave her house?
I don't know if this counts,
but about two hours earlier,
she was stripped of all her belongings
and was dragged to her master.
Who is her master?
Chief Censor.
Wait.
Gil-dong robbed
Chief Censor's storehouse yesterday.
Did anyone see smoke rising
from that house's chimney?
Yes, Your Highness.
I was told
they cooked rice in the morning.
What's the matter, Your Highness?
Go and bring that widow
to the constabulary at once.
I can finally move my shoulders.
How's your insomnia these days?
I think I'll only get some sleep
when I'm dead.
My lord!
The child has done no wrong!
Is something happening?
What a sweet baby.
The baby has put on some weight.
It means the mother had milk
to feed the baby.
You had no money to give to your master,
yet you had food to eat?
These were found in her house.
Where did you get this rice?
That's…
That's what I gave her last night.
Do you have a pimp now?
Eat it.
Come on. Eat it.
Seize all her possessions
and send her back empty-handed.
Yes, my lord.
My lord.
I beg your pardon,
but the baby and the mother
have been unable to eat
and suffering from malnutrition.
Please show mercy
and allow her to keep the rice at least.
My wife said that
you were a decent physician,
so I thought well of you.
But you don't know your place.
I'm a physician,
and these two are my patients.
That is why I beg this favor of you.
She needs to eat
for the medicine to take effect.
Unlike humans,
beasts die once their purpose is served.
That is how the world works.
Go home for now.
I will stop by later tonight.
I was going to stay quiet
for the time being, but…
Heading to Chief Censor's storehouse?
Who is he?
Do not worry.
This is not where you will die.
What?
Are you coming over?
Slave boy?
Why don't you just stay there?
I'd rather have some space between us.
No, I must be mistaken.
What are you doing?
That's his voice. I wasn't mistaken.
What?
What's the slave boy doing here?
I knew you wouldn't be an ordinary man,
but you're far more peculiar
than I thought.
Wait, that he knows I was going
to Chief Censor's storehouse means…
Gil-dong.
He knows me.
But how?
But before that, how does he look so sane?
Are you amazed by my insight,
seeing how I was already waiting here?
What are you nodding about?
What is happening?
I can't believe how I look either.
You may not believe me but it's true.
You may not believe this, but…
Is this all because I did not believe him?
Wait, does this mean…
I thought the silk clothes
he was wearing were borrowed.
Does this mean he's really not a slave?
When theft is your trade,
you're bound to get acquainted
with an aide or two.
No need to be so startled.
An aide?
He's a newly appointed aide.
He's a pale, well-groomed man.
This cannot be true.
There's no time to be in shock.
-I must run--
-Stop.
I won't chase you.
If I intended to catch you,
I would have tailed you
to find who you were.
You know where the thief is
and yet you won't give chase?
If Chief Constable finds out…
Go and bring that widow
to the constabulary at once.
Yes, Your Highness.
But we don't have any evidence.
Where do you think a widow
who didn't even have money for her master
got the rice?
Could it be Gil-dong…
The rumor that Gil-dong
is a righteous thief might be true.
And if it is true,
how much would it be worth?
Where could he be?
Yes.
I took it.
I ate it.
Because I was hungry.
And I bet other people who owe Gil-dong
did the same.
This was stolen. Do not tell anyone.
It is my fault
that the rumor is going around.
I was so happy to receive
what I didn't deserve
that I forgot about Gil-dong's request
and ran my mouth.
But I will not cause any more trouble.
I'm the one who was fed with stolen rice.
Arrest me.
The officer who questioned me
sent me all this?
He'd like you to just accept them.
The Grand Prince said to me,
"How could I blame
the widow and her child for their hunger?"
And how could I blame Gil-dong
for not overlooking the hunger
of a widow and her child?
And I don't have the answer yet.
Why does he say he wouldn't catch me?
But I will not support your theft either.
Neither will I blame Joseon
for ignoring corrupt officials. However…
However?
I will allow you
to look after your neighbors your way.
Does he want me to continue the theft?
Right.
The widow had a message for you.
Gil-dong always came by
whenever I was hungry and sick,
although I don't know how he always knew.
The smartest person I know
once said this to me.
Hunger alone is misery enough,
yet to suffer
my master's beatings as well…
I am so sick of this life.
I have been a physician
for only five years now,
but I have learned something in that time.
When a person is hungry and ill,
it is the heart that suffers most.
Is that so?
And when your heart is deeply hurt,
that is when
no medicine works.
No matter how fine the medicine,
it cannot reach a wounded heart.
That person said to me
that sometimes, it's not fancy medicine
but a bowl of rice prepared with love
that heals a person.
And that's exactly what happened to me.
THIS WAS STOLEN. DO NOT TELL ANYONE.
The rice I swallowed
through the lump in my throat…
reached and touched my heart deeply.
So each time he came by,
the warmth he left behind
made me so happy.
She said she was happy to have known you
and thanked you.
This is how I knew you'd go
to Chief Censor's storehouse tonight.
It's all thanks to the widow.
I thought you'd come back tonight
to see the widow and the baby
exploited by Chief Censor
based on what she told me.
And you're where I predicted you would be.
From now on,
stay within my expectations.
Just stay within
what I can handle.
What does this mean?
Does he really mean that?
But if you go beyond my forbearance
and threaten the foundations of Joseon,
I will arrest you.
Bear this in mind.
Just because I do not chase you
does not mean I let you go.
Isn't that Gil-dong?
He looks just like the sketch.
It's Gil-dong! Gil-dong is here!
Oh, no.
He was just stalling for time.
Wait.
Stop!
He's here!
Hasn't the arrest order been canceled?
It was canceled so urgently
that it seems it never reached
the officers already out on patrol.
There's a ball of cotton
instead of the arrowhead.
Enough with the act and get up.
This unnecessary chase
could put His Highness in danger.
Guard His Highness first.
Stop there!
Stop the attack!
What kind of twisted fate is this?
From now on,
stay within my expectations.
Just stay within
what I can handle.
I almost fell for it.
I hope he escaped safely.
HYEMINSEO
Why did he come here?
Is he after Gil-dong?
I saw the lantern was lit, so I came in.
Oh, no. What do I do?
Hyeminseo is closed now. Please leave.
Is it you?
It's you, isn't it?
Should I just run now?
It is you.
The silk shoes.
Silk shoes?
The flowery rain.
Flowery rain?
There you are.
Lady Flower.
What happened to your arm?
Did you get hurt?
You said you would only look.
Just looking won't do.
You must be close to the Grand Prince.
We are very close.
I heard he was a philanderer.
I told you to donate anonymously.
There are unsavory rumors
about Your Highness.
This should be made known.
They're my rumors.
Put a man on the Grand Prince.
Find out whom he meets and where he goes.
You didn't even realize you got hurt.
Are you always dull?
Does he know that
you're marrying a man in his 70s?
It will be interesting if he finds out.
What are you doing now?
I'm courting you.
Is there a man you hold dear?
Subtitle translation by Sunyoung Baek