They say it's like
a cloud swallowing the moon.
So that's when he shows up?
No.
That's how long it takes him
to rob a single storehouse.
So did you see him?
Indeed, I did.
The moment the cloud released the moon.
He was a Baekjeong!
It's the return
of Im Kkeok-jeong's spirit!
What are you talking about?
I heard he had a sharp, handsome nose,
and he's the prettiest man in Joseon.
That way!
What the heck? It's not a human.
It's a monster with fur all over its body.
What?
I thought he was a 100-year-old hermit.
Does a 100-year-old have the energy
to distribute ten thousand seok of rice
across the capital?
Oh, really?
So this thief is a handsome man
who wants to shack up with a widow?
Watch out for good-looking men.
Well, it's a monster covered in fur,
with monstrous strength.
Oh, for goodness sake.
-I told you.
-Ma'am.
I saw that great, righteous thief
with my own two eyes last night!
He's a Baekjeong.
There's been improvement.
For the next three days,
clean your eyes with salt water
and then rinse them with warm water.
Thanks, Eun-jo.
By the way,
you know eye problems
can affect your vision, right?
A pig?
I know. A chicken head.
What's that?
A dragon?
Baekjeong, my foot.
Oh, it's a snake head.
It's a chicken head.
Seok-sam, that punk.
His eyes lie just as much as his words do.
These herbs are good
for child malnutrition.
There's no way
he saw this righteous thief.
Well, how can a thief
possibly be righteous?
Do you really think so?
The granaries of corrupt officials
are filled with things
taken from the people.
Which means those granaries
rightfully belong to the people.
So it isn't theft.
It is merely giving back
what was taken from them.
You heard him.
Are you on the thief's side too, sir?
How could I ever take a thief's side?
I'm only speaking the truth.
Rumors are never wholly true.
So maybe
the name is fake.
The name?
People call him Gil-dong.
"A friend on the road"?
Is that what it means?
Well, some say that
it means "the rope on the ground."
This is a real headache.
The truth is lost amid countless rumors.
-Did I just say…
-Did you just say…
"lost"?
YI YEOL
GRAND PRINCE DOWOL
I told you,
when you're lost in the case,
you can always come to me.
He has good ears.
It's good to see you again,
Your Highness.
It has been a long time.
That said,
the moral order has collapsed.
This is no small matter.
Please have a seat here.
I know we're both busy,
so let us dispense with formalities.
And there is no need for thanks.
This isn't the first time I've
shared my wisdom with you thick-heads.
We are deeply grateful
for your constant help
with our investigations.
The great thief
who stole ten thousand seok of rice?
-Who are the victims?
-There are none.
Those crooked officials
couldn't come forward,
afraid their own sins would be exposed.
They just chose not to.
-And I wouldn't either, if I were them.
-Why is that?
Someone reported
that they saw Gil-dong here,
at the Chief Censor's storehouse.
That's right.
One of our slaves
saw something suspicious.
The storehouse is already full again.
The Chief Censor
must be blessed with fortune,
though he doesn't seem like it.
Well, the truth is…
You couldn't find anything stolen.
That's right, sir.
Everything is exactly as it was.
-Search the place.
-Yes, sir.
I found it!
It looks like a bowl of rice.
-Did Gil-dong leave this drawing?
-Yes, Your Highness.
Could it be…
Weigh the rice now.
How much is missing?
One sack should fill an entire jar,
but exactly three does are missing.
That means Gil-dong stole
just three does of rice.
This is why his thefts
were usually discovered much later.
And even when it's discovered,
the amount is too small to report.
Has anyone claimed to have received
the stolen goods from Gil-dong?
Not a single one.
He's just a petty thief
who steals for himself.
And people speak of him
as a righteous thief.
Are there
more of his drawings, like this?
Why does he leave these drawings?
If he didn't, no one would ever notice.
That's what I'm talking about.
It's like he's messing with us.
Well, apparently,
he's proud of his thefts.
Humans, by nature,
affirm their sense of worth
by revealing their strengths.
Oh, I get it.
Just like how you gather
all the court ladies to brag
every time you solve a case.
It means he's the kind of man
who craves attention as well.
Is that a question or a criticism?
I wouldn't dare. It's a mere question.
No more questions from now on.
I get why you spread out the drawings.
Gil-dong wants
to brag about his thefts everywhere.
And there are rumors
calling him a righteous thief.
He must be puffed up with pride.
Well, who do you think
started those rumors?
No way.
Gil-dong.
Seize those spreading the rumors.
The false rumors
are covering up the thefts,
so that's where we'll find the culprit.
Yes, Your Highness.
Your Highness,
aren't you supposed to have tea
with the Queen Dowager around 4:00?
Why are you saying that now?
You said no more questions--
Don't you know
how to say things as a statement?
Hey, wake up.
Wake up!
Is His Majesty here?
It's another Majesty!
What?
Your Majesty!
Why did it have to be you?
Couldn't you have made it
more convincing at least?
I'm here to have tea with the Prince,
so you should have made me think,
"My boy is taking a well-deserved nap"
and had me come back another time.
That is what you are here for!
We beg for mercy, Your Majesty!
His Majesty is keeping
a close watch on the Prince.
You people can't protect the Prince.
Send word to my brother that
we must hasten
Yeol's marriage arrangements.
Yes, Your Majesty.
YI GYU
THE KING OF JOSEON
They're trying to marry Yeol
to the Chief Censor's daughter?
Wouldn't that be wonderful?
If that happens,
the Chief Censor will start
protecting Grand Prince Dowol.
As if everyone's out
to get the Grand Prince.
Her Majesty frets too much.
This is all because I failed
to earn Her Majesty's trust.
It is my fault.
That is not true, Your Majesty.
Secretary Im.
What do you think I should do
to appease Her Majesty?
IM SA-HYEONG
CHIEF ROYAL SECRETARY
I have a family in mind
for Grand Prince Dowol's marriage.
The Commander-in-Chief in Goryeo--
I'm sure you know what you're doing.
It's my younger brother's marriage,
so see to it personally.
A military clan from Goryeo?
I wonder what they're doing now.
They must be growing rice
somewhere in the countryside.
What a sly fox you are.
If I'm a fox, what are you, Geum-nok?
GEUM-NOK
SUK-YONG
I'm a nine-tailed fox, of course.
Your Majesty.
SHIN YEO-GYEONG
QUEEN CONSORT
I hear my niece and
the Chief Secretary's son got engaged.
Yes, Your Majesty.
The Im family is seeking to expand
its influence through marriage ties.
Everyone knows their scheme,
yet there is no one to stop it.
It is truly grievous.
Oh, Geum-nok!
It tickles, Your Majesty!
I am deeply sorry
that such grievous misfortunes
keep befalling Your Majesty.
But please do not be disheartened.
My son will will look after your niece
with the greatest care.
IM JAE-I
IM SA-HYEONG'S SECOND SON
THE TALE OF SUKHYANG
SHIN HAE-RIM
THE QUEEN CONSORT'S NIECE
They call this erotic?
It's too bland.
Well.
It looks like we're really destined.
Pardon?
I didn't expect to meet my fiancée here.
Wait, are you…
My father is the Chief Royal Secretary.
This is the woman who is to be my wife.
Pay your respects.
Hello, I'm No-eul.
And this woman here will be my concubine.
No, maybe you already are.
If we went by who undressed first,
I would be the consort,
but I'll let you have that place.
It's great to see my wives get along.
Now that we're all here,
why don't we have a drink?
We'll be family.
That sounds lovely.
I should get going.
My brother is probably waiting for me.
Why don't you marry her,
instead of tormenting that lovely woman?
Marriage is a gamble.
-I want to win far more than what I stake.
-What?
In this country, from kings to slaves,
everyone uses marriage
to secure wealth, honor, power,
and higher status.
So I might as well play for higher stakes.
She's the Queen Consort's niece.
What could possibly be a higher stake?
Something like…
love.
How typical.
You highborn are all the same.
Yes, I'm trying to put together
a typical charade.
I have expectations to meet, after all.
Stay healthy, okay?
-Sir.
-Hello.
I'm here to pick up the herbs I asked for.
Sure. Just wait a second.
I'm back, Young Master.
-Wait, stop there.
-Yes?
I told you not to come in
wearing that physician's robe,
reeking of my patients.
I meant to change first,
but things were hectic
at the Hyeminseo today.
Do you think bringing home some money
suddenly makes you someone?
But I'm your family's slave.
-So what?
-What do you mean?
Could a slave be someone?
-Of course not.
-Exactly.
Right.
You're just being mean for no reason.
How dare you talk back to me?
Where did she go?
Mother!
-When did you get here?
-Just now.
I know you're tired. Give it to me.
Look at how dirty
the young master's socks are.
Is he secretly seeing a woman
at night or what?
Don't say that. He's not even married.
I'll hang them.
You go back and take the medicine.
Let's do it together.
Come on.
You need to take it while it's hot.
HONG MIN-JIK
HONG EUN-JO'S FATHER
Eun-jo, come to my room.
What is it you wish to say, my lord?
You can call me "Father" at home,
as I said.
How can I? I'm a concubine's daughter.
People would point fingers at you
if they heard that.
What is this?
From now on, wear these
whenever you go to Secretary Im's house.
Where did you get the money
to buy the silk clothes?
No, actually,
why would you want me to wear these
when I go to his house?
You must be aware
that his eldest son
has taken no concubine.
We will have your wedding soon.
I humbly beg you, please call it off.
I wish to live here with you and Mother
for the rest of my life.
My foolish child.
No parent would wish their child
to grow old alone.
It's time for you to live a woman's life.
I have never wanted a woman's life.
You have suffered enough in this house.
You have had enough.
You may be a concubine's child,
but I wish them to treat you with respect.
That's why I prepared these.
So be sure to wear them.
The officer at the constabulary
will be reprimanded.
Why not first fault the Prince
for lingering about the constabulary?
It was all for the security of the capital
and ultimately,
for the people and you as well, Mother.
Don't worry about me.
From now on,
live for one woman, not for me.
Marry the Chief Censor's daughter.
His family will be a great support to you.
Yes, Mother.
So you're doing it?
But let me meet her first.
I need to know about her personality.
I want to see if she's reliable,
and most of all,
if she's beautiful.
No, that is not how it's done.
I guess Gil-dong robbing that house
wasn't for nothing after all.
Have you made any progress
in catching that thief, Gil-dong?
I heard he robbed your storehouse too,
so I've been keeping a close eye on it.
I'm so relieved to hear that,
Your Highness.
Please excuse the humble refreshments.
I didn't expect your visit today.
The refreshments at our palace
pale in comparison to this.
So I had a look around the storehouse,
and I couldn't quite see…
Now, I see it.
This is my daughter.
Pay your respects.
This is Grand Prince Dowol.
I am Jin, of the Kim Family.
-Does your name "Jin" mean "beauty"?
-Yes, Your Highness.
My name is Yi Yeol.
"Yeol" means "happiness."
It seems like the two of us
are living up to our names.
Why don't we go hunting together sometime?
I was sheltered,
can't stand anything rough.
Stabbing, killing…
anything involving blood
just doesn't appeal to me.
Is that something you fancy?
As a woman,
I certainly do not fancy seeing blood.
What a shame.
Because that's what you need
to become a Grand Prince's wife.
Rivalry and intrigue are fundamental
to life in the royal court.
-Your Highness.
-There's no need for pretense.
It will only embarrass us both.
If you give birth to a prince,
he would be deemed a threat
to the crown prince.
You may witness your child poisoned,
or murdered under the guise of suicide.
But I suppose you know that much.
-In case of a conspiracy--
-Your Highness.
Your words can be heard beyond the fence.
Even if, after a bloody power struggle,
I were to ascend the throne
and you were to become Queen Consort,
you would soon be deposed.
And why would that be?
Your family may be wealthy,
but it holds no real power.
I don't think your family
can guard the Queen's palace.
But Your Highness--
A king cannot be a husband.
A king doesn't protect his woman.
He protects his throne.
Your father must know.
Because he is the one
who deposed His Majesty's mother.
Why did you refuse
the Chief Secretary's daughter?
Brother!
Come now.
I told you not to call me Brother.
Yes, Your Highness.
But why can I not call you Brother?
You are my brother.
Because our mother isn't my mother.
My birth mother is the deposed queen,
cast out of the palace
by political strife.
Do you understand what this means, Yeol?
It means you and I are enemies.
So, Yeol,
keep your brilliance
hidden from the world.
Keep yourself from my sight,
and do nothing,
unless
you want to lose your mother like me.
I could not protect my mother,
but you must protect yours.
To me, marriage is
a place of refuge.
Do you wish to go into hiding?
I must remain as unnoticed as possible.
Well, you certainly want to remain
unnoticed by Her Majesty today.
Do you think she'll kill me?
She definitely will, right?
Oh, my goodness!
Your Highness.
I'm so sorry!
Am I dead already?
I'm smelling death.
Dae-chu, what's this hole for?
Is it for breathability?
It's just ragged.
What?
They were the only clothes I could borrow.
Since we were rushing…
I am not going anywhere looking like this.
If you make me wear these rags
for more than an hour,
you will pay dearly for it.
I'll run to the palace and be right back!
-Did you see my grandfather?
-Yes, sir.
My father says my grandfather's bedsores
and complexion have improved greatly
since you began treating him.
I'm just doing
what I have been doing back in Hyeminseo.
Give her a little more
than her usual fee today.
Yes, sir.
Excuse me, sir.
About our marriage…
One.
How dare a lowlife like you
speak to me like that?
Do I look like a lowlife to you?
Even filthy water and ragged clothes
cannot conceal my nobility
and elegant bearing.
This rude wretch!
Look, you keep calling me wretch.
You wretch!
Are you asking for trouble?
You must have really lost your mind.
This is against the moral order.
Come with me to the constabulary.
My goodness. That mad wretch
is earning himself a hundred lashes.
That mad slave is digging his own grave.
Follow me.
What?
Let go of me.
Let me lead the way.
As a matter of fact,
I frequent the constabulary.
So let me lead the way.
It seems like
I need to beat some sense into you!
Where did he go?
Who are you?
Sir,
please do not soil your noble hands.
This man is a slave.
A slave?
This is none of your concern.
He's right. Please step back, my lady.
This madman doesn't know what he is doing.
Please show the generosity of a nobleman.
A nobleman's generosity
isn't for lowly slaves.
It is thanks to lowly slaves
who till the land and harvest the crops
that you can wear such fine clothes
and appear so well-fed
and radiant as you do.
And if this slaves dies,
who's going to feed the cows?
Is he from your household, my lady?
"My lady"?
Oh, "my lady."
Right. Yes.
He is my slave.
Who? Me?
Ever since
my grandfather passed away,
our family fell on hard times.
So every hand we have is precious.
But then he fell from a pear tree
and completely lost his mind.
So I always have to keep an eye on him.
I bet it's a lot of work.
My apologies. Please punish me instead.
No, that wouldn't be necessary.
Of course, it isn't.
Don't apologize without my permission.
Especially when it's on my behalf.
No one would dare punish me.
Also, I'm not anyone's slave--
What happened to my knees?
Who did this to my knees?
Did you kick me to my knees?
Look. I'm this country's--
He's been saying
he's possessed by a general's spirit
for the past few days.
And he keeps yelling like this.
Be quiet.
Does this slave
really belong to your family?
Yes.
He does.
He's my slave girl…
-Girl?
Slave boy!
Boy. He's my slave boy.
Slave boy?
Hello, Seung-baek.
Young Master?
If they find out I'm a slave, I'm done.
Thank you for forgiving us.
Now, please excuse us.
Let go.
I do not want you to regret anything.
Please, I don't want
to be beaten to death.
-Death?
-Yes. Come on. Let's go.
What's all this fuss about?
It was some madman.
He looks familiar.
Will you let go now?
I don't think they're following us.
Why did you run?
Well, my young master…
Wait a minute.
You know I saved your life, right?
It's his life that was spared.
Oh, my.
You weren't just pretending
to be a madman.
A madman?
Weren't you pretending to be mad
to escape punishment?
There was no one at the market earlier
who could dare punish me.
This man is seriously mad.
I can't believe how I look either.
I refuse to explain further.
I refuse to help you further too.
-Farewell.
-Not so fast.
There's something I need to know.
What did you mean when you said
you would be beaten to death?
That's why I followed you here,
so you'd better explain.
Of course it means that
once they find out it was a lie,
we would both be punished…
If I tell him I'm a slave as well,
he'll be utterly shocked.
Because you're not my slave.
I was trying to avoid punishment
for my lie. That's what I meant.
So why get involved in the first place?
Your punishment
would not have ended with you.
Your mother, your father
and even your relatives
would have gotten lashes.
What a nosy woman.
I know.
My nosiness is one of the few blessings
I was born with.
I don't like it either.
What are the rest?
Poverty, misery, sadness and tears.
Of all my misfortunes,
the one blessing I have
is my mother.
And my father.
Why is he looking at me like that?
I should stop answering him and go.
I'll get going now.
My silk clothes…
I can't let them get wet.
You're quite nimble.
I have never been rained upon in my life.
-You may not believe me, but it's true.
-Sure.
Because, if I were to fall ill,
several physicians
would be held to account.
You may not believe this either,
but it is true.
Sure.
-You don't believe me, do you?
-No.
What are you doing?
I don't want them to get muddy.
These are the first silk shoes and dress
I have ever had.
Is your family that badly off?
Even so, a young lady
shouldn't so easily bare her feet.
What's the big deal?
What are you doing?
You may not know this
because you haven't been rained upon,
but being in the rain,
it feels as though
all your sorrow is washed away.
I don't believe you.
It really does.
You may not believe it though.
Is it rain that just hit my back?
I think it was a thunderbolt.
I wish the thunderbolt hit your mouth too.
It's…
It's so cold. I can't move.
Take it off.
I see what you're doing.
You need to wring the water out of it
so it dries quickly.
Don't be so dramatic. It's just some rain.
This is the first time
cold water has touched my body.
My body has only ever touched
warm water fragrant with flowers.
Well, no one asked you to go stand there.
You said
those were your only silk clothes.
You weren't born with many blessings.
You might as well avoid the rain.
Well…
Thank you.
"Thank you"?
You're supposed to say "I'm honored…"
Pardon me. Did you see a man sitting here?
This is bad. He hates rain.
Do you not know how to do it?
My hands are not meant for tying knots.
You have never been rained upon
nor tied a knot on your jacket.
What do you even do?
Nothing. It's a very important task.
So that's how you lost your mind.
It seems the rain has stopped.
I'm good.
I'm throwing them away.
I will not let that foul-smelling thing
touch my body.
He's a madman.
Let's not waste words on him.
Since you threw them away, I'll take them.
What is your father's name?
Your family may be in decline,
but it still has a name.
Should I just tell him the truth now?
That I'm a slave like him?
Her face has hardened.
Has her family been completely wiped out?
Never mind, if you don't want to say it,
but do this for me.
On the day of the full moon,
come to Soha Village around 6:00.
Why should I do that?
I'd like to offer a generous reward
for your nosiness.
These are enough for me.
Well, then, take care.
They're not enough for me.
And I must
see you
once again.
Please come.
I will.
Reward, my foot.
A reward?
You're getting a punishment
for treating me like a mad slave.
Your Highness, you were here.
It's been over one hour.
Father.
Yes. Come in.
Father, is Eun-jo getting married?
That would mean even fewer wages
coming into this house.
Enough.
I heard you even bought her silk clothes.
Where did you get the money?
It's the money Eun-jo earned,
which I set aside little by little.
I will sell those silk clothes.
They're bought with a slave's money,
so they're mine.
Get out of my room.
You can't let Eun-jo go!
Get out of my room!
I humbly beg you
to postpone the wedding,
if only for a short while.
I must look after my ailing mother.
And ever since that incident,
my family is still badly off.
We need the money I earn.
I understand what you're saying,
but my grandfather has little time left.
Pardon?
The Old Master, sir?
My father does not wish
his father to meet a lonely death.
So he wanted to get him a concubine
who would look after him.
The man I was to marry was…
the Old Master?
You seem displeased.
Not at all, sir. I beg your pardon.
Make that face again,
and your entire family
will be cast out of that house.
You should be grateful
that your father and I are friends.
I am not like my father.
I would have slain
every living creature in your house
on the very day of the literati purge
if I were him.
Keep a clear head.
This marriage must happen, no matter what.
In Joseon, marriage is a transaction
for everyone.
From the king
down to a concubine's daughter like me.
So I will weigh the terms as well.
One.
Is that the lord?
Not even one nyang?
It took me ten full nights
to transcribe them.
The truth is…
These four books have too many errors.
Is that so?
My eyesight has grown dim with age.
Then deduct the errors from the payment.
I'm sorry I couldn't pay you more.
Don't worry. Thank you.
Excuse me, sir. I have a question.
When did the man who just left
start the transcription work?
About a year ago.
A year?
It's good for coughs. Brew it and take it.
How did you get this rare medicine?
He is Lord Hong Min-jik.
He spoke harsh truths to the king,
and was swept up in the literati purge.
He was stripped of his post,
and all his property was confiscated.
Eun-jo is here, my lord.
Yes, come in.
Are you coming from Secretary Im's house?
You look beautiful.
My lord.
Is the man I am to marry--
You mean, Seung-jae?
What about him?
Just as I thought,
Father does not know
that the marriage is to the Old Master.
He would never imagine
that it could be the Old Master.
Never mind.
I hear he even lives
in someone else's house.
It is a shame that such a great man
met with such a fate.
Make that face again,
and your entire family
will be cast out of that house.
Your Highness!
Come in.
A message has come from the constabulary.
So they've caught onto Gil-dong.
Gil-dong?
I don't know anything.
I only know him
by what I've heard from others.
If you cannot confess
who you heard it from,
you may be punished as an offender.
Pardon?
You cannot be serious, sir.
She's a woman.
She's a widow with a child.
I'm just saying.
Well…
I did see Gil-dong that night.
He was jumping from roof to roof.
It can't be her.
You see a tiger and think it's a pig.
What do you know?
What did you say?
Tell me exactly what you saw
without exaggeration.
He's a Baekjeong. I'm sure of it.
What's that?
I saw him only dimly, but I'm sure of it.
He was wearing a Baekjeong's mask?
Farewell, sir.
Wait for me.
Are you sure
you want to let the widow go?
I'm letting her go for a reason.
I saw him only dimly, but I'm sure of it.
You see a tiger and think it's a pig.
What do you know?
They seemed to be hiding Gil-dong.
They must know him.
You.
-You'd better stop running your mouth.
-What?
Well, you know why I ran my mouth.
I said, wait for me.
Prepare a wanted sketch of Gil-dong,
and keep a close watch on the widow.
If we follow her closely,
we'll catch Gil-dong.
Yes, Your Highness.
Are you going back to the palace now?
I have a plan for today.
Please come.
I will.
Soon, it will be time for punishment.
Eun-jo!
I'm sorry I'm late.
Something urgently came up.
The baby just fell asleep.
Thank you.
I will see you later at night.
I need to go somewhere.
Very well. I'll see you.
How do you do, my lord?
Yes, Eun-jo.
I have something to say.
My lord. Please step outside.
These are for Eun-jo's wedding.
-Did Chief Secretary Im send these?
-Yes, my lord.
Store them safely
and do not let anyone lay a hand on it.
We will choose an auspicious day
and hold the wedding.
My lord,
all the wedding gifts have been delivered.
Very well.
Lord Hong is not aware
that this marriage is
to the Old Master.
He must have misunderstood what I said.
I know he adores you
even though you're a concubine's daughter.
You may be a daughter to him,
but to me, you're just a slave.
Then please let him
keep misunderstanding it.
Until the wedding day,
please let my family believe
that I am to marry the young master.
And why must I do so?
Lord Hong is not the kind of father
who would marry his daughter off
to a widower in his seventies.
You must know his character
as well, my lord.
And
if Lord Hong were not where he is now
because of the literati purge,
you would not have asked such a favor
of a man who was once
the Minister of War.
Are you saying I dishonored your father?
Very well. Go on.
Let it be said that this marriage
was solely my own desire.
My desire to live in comfort
under the protection of a powerful family.
What a truly devoted daughter you are.
I could never compare to you, my lord.
My father will never rise
from his sickbed.
That means
you will never be able
to live a woman's life.
Does causing your father grief
concern you more than that?
I would spend the rest of my life
living only with Lord Hong and my mother.
I have no regrets,
even if I cannot live a woman's life.
If you have such resolve,
why not refuse it?
When Lord Hong's property was confiscated,
you took in our household, my lord,
and helped us keep our home at least.
I'm merely grateful that
I can repay your kindness in this way.
It's for her filial piety.
Such a bright child
was born to a concubine.
He must have felt deep regret.
I have nothing to lose in this deal.
One.
Both the house and Lord Hong are safe now.
Mother can live a comfortable life now.
One.
I'm marrying into a powerful family.
I have grown children
and even grandchildren now.
One.
And my husband will be…
Eun-jo…
I will take care of your mother,
so do not worry
and live as a woman
sharing a life of grace and love
with your husband.
There is no marriage in Joseon
that trades in love.
And it applies even less
to a slave like me.
They say one feels unsettled
on the day before the wedding.
Maybe that's true.
That means
you will never be able
to live a woman's life.
Do I regret it now?
I didn't realize
I walked all the way here.
What is he doing here?
On the day of the full moon,
come to Soha Village around 6:00.
That was today?
Has he been waiting all along?
How did I end up here?
How strange.
Of all days,
of all times,
and
of all people…
If I am no longer allowed
to live a woman's life…
If tonight is my last chance…
What took you so long?
Do you have any idea
how long I've been waiting--
That…
That would be my reward.
Your Highness.
Why is your face red?
I just got…
robbed now.
What did they steal?
Well…
I must have lost my mind.
Why did I do that?
Where did she go?
Oh, dear. It's getting late.
It's the curfew hour!
Close the gates!
Please forgive me
for my madness earlier today,
and forgive me in advance
for my future nosiness.
Maybe I missed her.
You.
I will catch you no matter what.
Security is especially tight today.
Gil-dong was the one
with the Baekjeong's mask.
If the woman kissed first,
it must be love.
Well, I do have the looks for it.
We must find him.
Has anyone seen this woman?
Why would you go to such lengths?
It's disgusting to see
a lowly concubine's daughter
acting like his sister.
He saw a suspicious man.
Heading to Chief Secretary's storehouse?
There you are, Gil-dong.
Subtitle translation by Sunyoung Baek