There you are.
Lady Flower.
He's not here for Gil-dong.
But how?
The notice board.
Should you be this man, or know of him,
please come forward to Physician Hong.
How he came here doesn't matter now.
Let's stay composed.
That man is an aide.
I'm only making myself look suspicious.
You look quite embarrassed from the back.
Or am I just imagining it?
Oh, dear!
It is you!
That's why your voice sounded familiar.
For someone who didn't recognize me,
you turned around pretty fast.
What?
No way.
I wouldn't have recognized you
and then pretended not to.
It's quite dark tonight, so…
It's bright.
The moon is shining brightly.
Exactly.
A strange man barged in
under the bright moonlight,
so I naturally took a step back.
This is a time when a man and a woman
should keep their distance.
I see.
So now you want to keep your distance.
What about the other night?
About the other night…
-Well--
-Say little.
Yet convince me.
Unexpected feelings?
I'm fine with that too.
As you can see,
I lied about my class,
and there's no excuse.
So I have
no explanation that could convince you
to excuse my rudeness toward a nobleman.
But most of all,
about leading you on--
Lead me on?
I know that
just an apology
cannot excuse that behavior.
A mistress and a slave, my foot.
Does this mean you ran away that night
because you knew my class?
Not at all.
I was wearing silk clothes too
when we first met at the market.
-Why?
-What?
Why? What are you getting at?
Well…
It's like a complicated
and somewhat impulsive--
Mistake?
Yes, that's the right word.
Don't you think that's exactly
what it shouldn't have been?
I apologize.
Whatever the punishment may be,
I will accept it without complaint.
Too bad.
Punishment was never my concern.
So you want me to take the initiative
and go to the constabulary.
Yes. Are you still here?
I'm on my way.
Though it was a misunderstanding,
you saved the life
of the dullard slave boy.
Let this repay what you did that day.
To be fair, that was my carelessness too.
What happened to your arm?
Did you get hurt?
It's not a big deal.
Let me take a look.
You said you would only look.
Just looking won't do.
Stopping the bleeding is enough.
That's what I came here for after all.
Isn't it because you saw the notice?
What notice?
Nothing.
Does that mean
this is a coincidence too?
Well,
a coincidence means
an unexpected encounter,
but I had too many expectations.
And my plea was heard.
What do you mean?
If you were in my place,
wouldn't you have been desperate
to catch you too,
after you ran away like that?
I see.
It's a stab wound. How did you get it?
I was grazed by an arrow.
An arrow, at this late hour?
What happened?
I was helping someone escape.
Helping someone escape?
Things went awry,
and I ended up putting someone on the run.
In any case,
it is still quiet out tonight.
It probably means
that person escaped safely.
Just stay within
what I can handle.
Was I mistaken?
Stop!
Could he have said that
to the officers, not Gil-dong?
If that's the case, he got this wound
because of me.
What's the matter?
What? What do you mean?
You keep staring at it.
Because I couldn't see the wound well.
Please move this way.
In any case,
I don't know the whole story,
but the person you helped
must surely be grateful.
I don't think so.
He must be feeling bitter, thinking,
"This wretch fooled me."
I'm sure it wouldn't last long.
No.
I can hear him faintly,
cursing at me.
No way! I would never…
think he would do that.
I mean, I wouldn't if I were him.
There's no need to comfort me.
He was hit by an arrow?
Did you see it?
No, one of the soldiers slipped
and loosed his bow.
This is a grave matter.
-Find the Grand Prince at once!
-Yes, sir!
The wound isn't that deep,
but it might leave a scar.
When it becomes light,
make sure to go to a private physician.
Here, at the Hyeminseo,
we don't have enough herbs
to dress the wound properly.
How much are you lacking?
We never have enough herbs
for the flood of patients we see each day.
Is that so?
You look like you're treating
a gravely ill patient.
Treating your wound with care
is the least I can do.
Well,
I'm taking it just as seriously.
It may be best that you do not.
For a second,
I wished my injury was worse.
Worse?
You cannot make that kind of joke
in the Hyeminseo.
I mean it. I always have.
Even that night,
when I was waiting for someone.
It was not like me.
You seemed confused.
And it intrigued me.
I thought
I could share in that confusion too.
All that, not knowing
it was a mere mistake.
About what happened that night,
let me apologize again--
Don't bother.
You must be upset--
I'm not upset.
But you look really upset.
I'm really not…
Your apology is what upsets me.
No need to come outside.
It seems like our coincidence ends today.
He looks upset even from the back.
Was there something wrong with my apology?
Where could she possibly be?
Your Highness.
I still haven't found this woman.
I apologize.
What do you mean by that?
I'm offering my apologies.
I'll find her tomorrow at all costs.
Exactly.
You made a mistake,
so you had to apologize twice.
Would you like me
to apologize three times?
No. And no more apologies from now on.
You are here, Your Highness!
How is your injury?
It's all right, as you can see.
Have you injured yourself?
-Who did this?
-Put it back.
What happened to Gil-dong?
He ran away without even looking back.
How cold of him.
I can't believe we met again.
I may actually grow fond of him.
Eun-jo!
Come quickly.
What are you doing here?
It's cold outside.
Earlier today,
I was questioned at the constabulary
about Gil-dong.
What? Let me see. Are you all right?
I'm all right.
That's not the problem.
Come with me.
Are you saying
the aide at the constabulary
sent all these?
Yes.
What did the aide look like?
He has a face as fair as the first snow,
his eyes as clear as crystal.
Truly a man of remarkable beauty.
I see.
Are we really talking
about the same person?
What did you say?
Nothing.
He sounds like a nice person,
showing you such kindness.
Oh, dear.
I'm glad
that it was a misunderstanding.
What?
This is what His Majesty said.
"The censors' remonstrances are becoming
more and more flattering."
"They're all lies."
Are you saying
our remonstrances to His Majesty
must first be approved by you
because of that?
That is utter madness!
Flattery too
requires wit.
Here. Have a look.
Look at your greed.
The tributes you extorted from the people.
Please give us more time!
The land you seized from the people.
The slaves you beat to death.
Every one of them
represents your greed.
I did hear
of your vile habit
of gathering ammunition
against the officials.
So this confirms it.
Last time, I had no chance to show you
this because of Grand Prince Dowol.
Are you blackmailing me?
Let us call it camaraderie.
Because I want you
to remain in that position
more than anyone else.
What?
Did you really take
all the wedding gifts
back to Chief Secretary Im's house?
With this back carrier?
Why did you do that?
That's what they paid for Eun-jo!
Have you no shame?
Think of Eun-jo.
She set out again at dawn today
to tend to ailing women.
My lord, please stop.
I wish
Eun-jo had been born
the eldest son of this household.
A fool like me
should have been born a slave!
Please stop, Young Master.
The exam results were announced today.
And I failed, of course.
I know shame,
so I will not ask for comfort.
Did you get the red pass?
Please, no congratulations.
First place?
You sly one.
So you weren't just idling all this time.
What's that?
Lord Hong Min-jik
sent back the wedding gifts.
That old geezer Hong
just can't let go of his pride.
What?
You were abroad studying before,
so you must not know Lord Hong.
He acts all righteous,
as if he's better than everyone else.
Father looks out for him
because they're friends,
but that man disgusts me.
I will make his daughter's life miserable
the moment she sets foot in this house.
You don't need to be so harsh
with your concubine.
As if.
She's being sold
as our grandfather's concubine, not mine.
She will be a caretaker.
What?
Apparently, that girl begged
to keep this information from Lord Hong.
You stood in a nobleman's way.
Forgive me, my lord!
Please forgive me, my lord!
Please forgive me!
All of you, show your respects.
What's all this?
The royal court has sent us
medicinal herbs.
Who in the royal court sent them?
Grand Prince Dowol.
That should cover a year's worth
of the Hyeminseo's herb supply.
How generous.
The physician of the royal court said
His Highness is exceptionally handsome.
It must be nice to work in the court.
You can see His Highness there.
This is all great,
but isn't this a bit random?
Her Majesty does not wish
to receive visitors.
Please tell Her Majesty
I'll return tomorrow.
To continue where we left off,
all the medicinal herbs you sent
to the Hyeminseo were for their patients?
Yes.
She said they never have enough herbs
for all the patients.
So I had to do it.
-This is great.
-What do you mean?
The physician who treated you
must be in shock by now.
-Why?
-"Oh!"
"The man I treated a few days ago
was the Grand Prince!"
Like this.
I told you to donate anonymously.
Were they bestowed under my name?
Yes. There are unsavory rumors
about Your Highness.
This should be made known.
They're my rumors.
Now that they know, why not visit
and encourage them in person?
There's no need.
It may help soothe
the Queen Dowager's anger.
I like that pretext.
Now, bring me the finest-looking horse
from the Royal Stables.
Now?
And on your way back,
stop by the Office of Royal Attire
and pick up the vest
made with silk from the Ming.
Is that necessary?
You keep answering with questions.
I apologize…
Right. I'm not allowed to apologize.
That was just me talking to myself.
Move!
You're going to be married soon.
You don't need ribbons.
You should be looking at hairpins.
You need one to pin up your hair
the morning after the wedding night.
Are you making fun of me?
What's wrong?
You even read the erotic book to study.
I was merely trying to understand.
I wanted to understand it,
so I could hate it less.
It's the lord.
What? Where?
Once he finds out
we came out without permission,
we'll be in serious trouble.
Get on your knees.
We must confess our wrongdoing and--
Run!
Run? Run where?
Where to?
Halt.
-Let's take another route.
-Yes, my lord.
Did I get caught?
I'm so in trouble.
Wait, he's from…
Excuse me.
Please help me.
I don't know whose daughter she is,
she must be the bane of the family.
I believe you're out of mortal danger now.
I'm alive.
Is he the Grim Reaper or something?
He's my brother.
He believes it is dangerous
for women to go outside.
I appreciate your help today.
Take care.
Dae-chu.
My lady.
Kkot-sim,
am I the invisible type?
Pardon?
If he doesn't remember me,
I must not have made
much of an impression, right?
Hello? Anybody in there?
So, I must wait in that line
to be treated?
That will not be necessary,
if you say you're the Grand Prince.
Be quiet.
Are you not here for an inspection?
There will be no inspection.
It'll only cause disruption.
Look! Are you okay?
Look here! Wake up!
Sir.
Eun-jo.
Let's carry her.
No, we must calm her down first.
If we move her now,
it will worsen her seizure.
-Please bring a physician.
-I will.
Ma'am.
Can you hear me?
Don't try to fight back, relax.
Relax your body and just lean on me…
We just need to stay with her
until a physician comes?
Ma'am.
Breath with me. Follow me.
One.
You're doing great.
Again. One.
One.
-One.
-What happened?
She had a seizure. It has just subsided.
-Move her inside.
-Yes, sir.
Let's go.
Did he leave?
Are you looking for me?
Thanks for helping me with the patient.
I brushed off the dirt and dust.
But the fine fabric has been ruined.
If you need compensation…
I need no compensation.
But this is troubling me again.
I know.
Your hands are not
for tying knots on your robe.
What are you doing? I just tied it.
Leave it.
My hands can bind up a wound though.
Later.
I'll do it later.
You treated my wound the other day
so now we're even.
My position does not allow me
to live indebted to others.
Sure. Now we're even then.
You didn't even realize you got hurt.
Are you always this dull?
You saw how chaotic it was.
I can feel the pain only once I'm relaxed.
What is your name?
Eun-jo, of the Hong family.
Sir.
Why do you ask?
Because I'm curious.
Why did you come here?
I wish I knew that too.
Are you here for another apology--
No.
I said I was not interested
in your impulses anymore.
I see.
It seems to be fine silk.
I will return it later.
What's that?
We received some medicinal herbs
from Grand Prince Dowol.
So I was making a list of them.
I see.
Grand Prince Dowol.
Actually, that's why I'm here.
Dig up every bit of dirt on Im Sa-hyeong.
Yes, my lord.
What on earth made you so angry
that you made this mess?
Do you know how much these are worth?
Answer me!
I'm still talking.
Where are you going?
-My head hurts.
-My lady.
-Clean that up.
-Yes, my lady.
Everything from here to there
was sent by Grand Prince Dowol.
I'll make sure His Highness knows
they arrived safely.
Continue what you were doing.
You must be close to the Grand Prince.
You're even carrying out
a secret inspection for His Highness.
We are very close.
I hear he's handsome.
What do you think?
What?
Those rumors are accurate.
What else did you hear?
Tell me everything.
That he's an idler
who's always roaming about,
and that he's a scoundrel.
That must be to explore the world
and broaden his horizons.
What else…
I heard he was a philanderer
who changes women every other day.
Now that's completely untrue.
It's his first!
First?
Am I making excuses for him?
That was inconsiderate of me.
I should have watched my words.
That I'm making excuses
means that I'm bothered.
You're close to him.
Of course you're bothered.
No.
I wasn't until now.
No matter what others say.
Pardon?
What does this mean?
Is everything sorted now?
These herbs are a token
of the Grand Prince's kind heart.
They shall not be wasted.
Yes, sir.
Superintendent, you've seen through
the Grand Prince's goodwill.
Grim Reaper?
Who are you?
He is…
Never mind.
I have no wish to exchange greetings
with a philanderer who keeps
someone's precious daughter at his side
in broad daylight.
Philanderer?
You may not understand,
but there's something hidden
in that picture
that you must never find out.
In other words, it's a misunderstanding.
What is a misunderstanding?
The lady wouldn't have hidden her face
if there were nothing to be ashamed of.
I don't care if you misunderstand me,
but there's nothing between us.
I see.
I know the face. I've seen it.
You don't believe me.
That's not important right now.
It is now.
What?
I don't know anything
about his private life.
Please do not judge him
solely by what you see.
He even helped me just a while ago.
And aside from that,
he serves at the constabulary.
So that speaks to his integrity.
I was wondering where you went.
If you've seen one, you've seen them all.
I forbid you
from entering my Hyeminseo.
Forbid me?
He forbade me.
How did you stand me all this time?
I can't stand this though.
I will tell him the truth
and hold him accountable.
Just leave it.
-Pardon?
-We can't say it now.
It'll only prove that I'm a philanderer.
Yes, Your Highness.
By the way,
the female physician from earlier,
she seemed somewhat familiar.
He serves at the constabulary.
Have I ever mentioned the constabulary?
The realgar antidote
we've received from the envoy
should take effect.
Your skin affliction
never seems to improve.
I'm tired.
It'll relieve the pain.
Get some sleep.
When did you get here?
I came straight from the Hyeminseo.
The lady urgently requested the tonic.
What's all this?
The lord had a fit of temper.
So I picked out the things
that could still be put to use.
What are you going to use
the burnt book for?
For the privy.
Like this.
This was in his room?
I was told
that you donated medicinal herbs
to the Hyeminseo.
Yes, it just happened that way.
Just as with Gil-dong.
I see now
that you care deeply for the people.
For the people?
Do you think I did it for the people?
Then what was it for?
It makes me look cool.
I must get going.
Playing constable is getting boring now.
I might start hanging around
the Ministry of Taxation.
Aren't you tired of always roaming around?
Those who are idle
are always the busiest, after all.
Your Highness. I remember now.
The female physician from earlier,
she's the one
you were waiting for that night.
The bandit.
You realize that now?
That said, I have a question.
I keep making excuses--
Please wait here. I'll take a look.
A cotton-tipped arrow?
Gil-dong.
So, you want to talk to me in private.
Is this the Chief Censor's…
This was in his room?
It was burning in the brazier,
so I took it out.
How could this be?
If this comes to light,
can I bear the consequences?
It could put everyone in danger.
Why? What does it say?
It's perfect for privies.
I will allow you
to look after your neighbors your way.
Actually, I've always wanted
to read this book.
Can I have it?
All the corrupt acts he has committed
since serving as the governor
of Pyongan Province
are recorded in great detail.
I understand why you gave this to me.
But didn't I tell you
that I will not support your theft
nor will I blame Joseon
for ignoring corrupt officials?
And by that, I meant…
I would do nothing.
If you thought I was a good man
after seeing one kind act,
you are mistaken.
I'm not the kind of person
who makes a show of justice.
If you do not wish
to die before your time,
stick to your petty theft
for your neighbors, nothing more.
Bringing down a single corrupt official
will not change this country.
Who's there?
Let him go.
Who was it?
It was Gil-dong.
Is this note from Gil-dong?
It seems like it's a message for you.
"Thank you for last night."
"I came across this book by chance."
I suppose I made too much
of one random kind act.
"I believe it will be of more use to you
than to me, a mere thief."
"A mere thief"?
What's the matter?
He's a mere thief, he says.
Pardon?
Why so eager?
Why always step forward
as if it were your problem?
You're a mere thief.
How annoying.
What is that?
I need to meet him.
Why that look?
Whom do you wish to meet?
My brother.
I pay my respects, Your Majesty.
It's good to see you, my brother.
How long has it been?
The night of the Gyeongo Year
was the last time.
It feels like yesterday
when you pointed
your sword at me that night.
Very well.
Whom will you point at today?
It's handwritten.
I came across it
while I was at the constabulary.
And the crimes listed there have been
confirmed to be true by the aides.
You could've handled it
within the constabulary.
If I submit a petition,
the Chief Censor will move to stop it
before it goes public.
So you wish me to punish him
before the eyes of all.
What if I choose not to act as you wish?
I have no particular wish.
And I shall not.
Your Majesty knows this well.
How heartless of you.
You once discussed marriage
with this family.
Having a greedy father-in-law
will bring me down anyway.
I know you would call it justice,
but what's your real intention?
Blast.
I don't want to be ashamed of myself
in front of this man
who is nobody.
What?
That's right.
I know it's childish,
but he hurt my pride.
Why did you meet His Majesty?
I suppose I must go to His Majesty
if I wish to see you
because you never allow me
into your chamber.
How could you…
Tell me.
What did His Majesty say?
Tell me!
Can't you see your mother is worried sick?
This is why
I must be idle even more.
He said he's ashamed of himself.
At least I can spare my younger brother
what little pride he has left.
For the sake of my dignity,
as his brother.
Eun-jo!
No one here knows how to read.
She's here.
Give me a moment.
What does it say?
Come on.
Read it out for us.
Sure.
"Chief Censor Kim Deok-han
extorted the property of the people,
already impoverished
by the continued famine…"
What is all this about?
"…seized their land
through ruthless usury,
eventually driving them to destitution."
"This truly goes against
basic human morality."
"The seized land
shall be returned to the peasants
to right the wrongs."
"His office and property
shall be confiscated,
and he is sentenced to exile
pursuant to the law."
"This is to punish
-a corrupt official…
-…a corrupt official
for plundering the people's granary."
My word!
It's like sweet rain after a long drought!
The world
has not entirely turned against us!
What is this?
Maybe it wasn't
just one act of kindness after all.
STATE TRIBUNAL
How dare you?
I asked how the Grand Prince
obtained the book.
You betrayed me,
and now you lay the blame on me?
So the Chief Censor did not
hand the ledger to the Grand Prince?
The Chief Censor may be foolish,
but he would not have destroyed himself.
But no one
is aware of the ledger,
save you and me, Father.
You should quietly sound out
how much His Highness knows.
His Highness does not yet know
the ledger was mine.
Had he known,
it would not have been
only the Chief Censor who was dismissed.
Put a man on the Grand Prince.
Find out whom he meets and where he goes.
Observe his every move.
So, this is it!
Oh, dear. It smells delightful.
Seok-sam, hurry over.
Seok-sam is here!
Chil-seok, what are you doing? Come here.
-Come here.
-Come quickly.
Take this, Seok-sam.
I'll drink from the bottle.
-Come on. Let's drink together.
-Let's drink.
Please at least go
and share a drink with them.
They think you're an aide
and wish to show their gratitude
with the food they've made
despite their humble circumstances.
I usually make sure
to take credit for what I do,
but I'll be busy tonight.
-Dae-chu, you go in my stead.
-Me?
Meet me around 8:00 in the evening
at the gate.
And you,
from tomorrow,
keep watch on Gil-dong's movements.
May I ask why?
The Chief Censor's crimes
listed in the ledger
are not something
a petty thief could have gathered.
Do you think someone is behind Gil-dong?
Whether someone stands behind him
or he came upon it by chance, as he wrote,
I must find out.
Yes, Your Highness.
And now I am curious
to see his face.
She's being sold
as our grandfather's concubine.
She will be a caretaker.
Does life treat you well?
I apologize
for my rudeness the other day.
I didn't know you were their second son.
Please forgive me.
I will make his daughter's life miserable
the moment she sets foot in this house.
I will consider
my apology accepted.
Now, if you'll excuse me.
Call off the wedding.
My wedding?
May I ask why?
I cannot stomach
living in this house with those animals.
I will keep it in mind.
In Joseon, carrying a concubine's blood
means you're flawed.
And that means
someone like you will be treated
like an animal in this family.
I do know that much.
No.
You don't know.
Remember this humiliation.
Once you set foot in this family,
you will feel it tenfold.
My brother has a temper like none other.
Is this a warning?
Call it charity.
Sometimes, I can act like a good man too.
Why are you doing this to me?
Lord Hong sent back all the wedding gifts.
He seems to genuinely care
for someone as lowly as you.
My lord did that?
You really care for each other,
like a real father and daughter.
What a pitiful family.
I must see my lord!
Eun-jo.
Not you as well.
Young Master is right.
We could have taken everything.
So what if we lack a bit of shame?
It would have made your life
much more comfortable.
Was it so hard for you?
He said he wouldn't let you
take any more burden.
He said retrieving my slave register
and keeping this house
were burdens you're already bearing,
so he would pay them all back,
little by little.
That's what he said to Chief Secretary Im.
Don't say anything.
If anything, blame me
for being carried away
by the wedding gifts.
It's getting late.
I must go prepare dinner.
I cannot believe this.
How am I supposed to get married now?
Is anyone here?
Where is she?
What are you doing there?
How did you get here?
I was just passing by.
The moon is shining brightly,
and
I have something to reclaim.
Right, the tie.
I washed it and kept it at home.
Give me a second. I'll be right there.
No.
Stay there.
What were you looking at?
Nothing. The night.
I hate the night.
It's calm and still,
as if nothing has happened.
That's why I like about the night.
Especially when I see it
from the roof like this.
From here,
people seem small, houses seem small,
even the palace seems small.
It makes my worries seem small as well.
What are your worries?
I can be kind and be supportive.
No, thank you.
If someone actually showed support,
I would want to give up everything.
Then give it up.
Whatever it is,
you can give it up just this once.
If you want, I can help you give it up.
You're talking
as if you know what it's about.
I don't need to know.
Whatever it is,
I have the power to do that.
Does that mean
I have some solid backing now?
I feel relieved, this much.
Only that much?
It should be bigger than just this much.
Right.
I happened to overhear
that the Chief Censor's case
was investigated by the constabulary.
Actually, I've been wondering about this.
How did you know
I was at the constabulary?
I don't remember saying it.
Well…
It tastes delightful.
What's this about?
You said you wouldn't see us
till you pass the exam.
Congratulations.
Let's forget the other day and move on.
Nothing happened at home?
What do you mean?
Your lowly sister.
Don't talk about that girl.
It kills my appetite.
What?
What happened to all that praise for her?
What's wrong? You don't look well.
Almost all the patients
who come to the Hyeminseo
after being struck by arrows at night
are patrol officers from the constabulary.
That makes sense.
So I assumed you were
from the constabulary too.
I heard about the rice
you sent Lady Dong-ju as well.
You know the widow too?
How?
The Chief Censor
often laid hands on others.
So his slaves frequented the Hyeminseo.
I'm not surprised.
Thank you.
Why would you say that?
Because
I know them pretty well too.
An idler like me
doesn't deserve any thanks.
You should thank someone else.
Who?
You don't know him.
There's this man
who is just as nosy as you.
He's talking about Gil-dong.
All I did was make sure
his heart came across.
Your wish for his heart to come across
shows your own heart.
I told you, that's not it.
To me, you seem like a good person.
You must not know yourself very well.
Or are you just pretending?
You haven't known me
long enough to say that.
I can tell
from years of dealing with people.
In any case,
I'm so glad that you solved this case.
How fortunate.
"Fortunate"?
What do you mean by that?
I mean
you're so smart
and everything went well. That's all.
Don't say that so easily.
Pardon?
Poverty, misery,
sadness and tears.
It sounds like I might be
one of the few fortunate things
among all that misfortune you have.
All I said was that it was fortunate.
Follow me.
I don't have the tie, but I will
change the cloth around your wound.
Come, before the Superintendent
kicks you out.
No one's getting kicked out.
Jae-i.
Let's have one more drink.
Let go.
It's the Hyeminseo.
All right.
I will teach the wench a lesson today!
As I said many times,
bans, orders, permissions, aid,
those are things that only I can do.
I was just joking.
You won't be kicked out, so don't worry.
I have no such worry.
If the Superintendent finds out
who he banned from entering,
he will be devastated.
That's what I worry about.
You keep saying that.
So you're from a family
with that much power?
One of the most powerful in Joseon.
That's all you need to know for now.
And I'm keeping this from you
so you don't get too shocked.
So I treated someone so great
like a dullard.
It must have felt really unfair.
It felt unfamiliar.
It felt unfamiliar
to see a woman less than half my size
standing in front of me to protect me.
This madman doesn't know what he is doing.
Please show the generosity of a nobleman.
So I was intrigued.
And ever since then…
This is nonsense.
There really is such a thing?
What do you mean?
Why are you looking at me like that?
You're embarrassing me.
I feel the same.
I'm embarrassed as well.
Pardon?
What I'm about to say
is even more embarrassing.
Is there a man you hold dear?
Why do you ask?
I don't care if you do.
Are you free tomorrow?
Make some time for me.
What are you doing?
I'm courting you.
From now on,
I want to do it more properly.
Well…
I'm getting married soon…
How did you…
What is this?
A man and a woman
at this late hour?
Who is that man?
Introduce yourself first.
Give me a moment.
What's the matter?
You seem flustered.
This is interesting.
Am I seeing what I'm not supposed to see?
Pardon?
This is clearly a tryst.
And an uninvited guest
has arrived at just the right time.
Does he know that
you're marrying a man in his 70s?
Your face is getting
more and more interesting.
It will be even more interesting
if he finds out.
Hey.
You tell me.
Who do you think
I am?
I hope this is the last time we meet.
Should I steal her?
I'm the Grand Prince.
I can steal whatever I want.
Broken heart? Is it really that hard?
Call off the wedding.
Do you want to be sold that badly?
A fight for survival,
like you said, for a lowly girl like me.
Be honest with me.
You're avoiding me now.
You haven't known me that long.
How much longer do you need
to understand me?
I just need you to say one thing.
That it's all right.
Subtitle translation by Sunyoung Baek